太空
Space.
人类在其无垠的广阔里
Humankind has been gazing
已凝望了上千年
into its infinite vastness for millennia.
现在我们将人类的知识推到极限
Here we are pushing the boundaries of our knowledge,
进入冒险旅程
venturing out into...
什么 这些乐高迷你人偶在这里做什么
What? What are LEGO minifigures doing out here?
这些见鬼的玩具到底在外太空干什么呢
What the heck are toys doing in outer space?
要回答这个问题 就先要开始回到
To answer that, first we have to start our story
那美好古老星球--地球来讲我们的故事
back on good old planet Earth.
这里是美国西北的太平洋地区
Here in the U.S.'s Pacific Northwest,
一个叫托林的男孩
a boy named Thorin makes
正在为自己打造的战役场景做着最后一刻的准备
last-minute preparations on his battle scene.
在荷兰罗莎正在她的客厅里建造一辆小轿车
In the Netherlands, Rosa is building a car in her living room.
在中国的上海
In Shanghai, China,
雨航玩一套新的乐高套来庆祝他的生日
Yuhang celebrates his birthday with a new LEGO set.
在科罗拉多州的丹佛
And in Denver, Colorado,
埃文像世界上许多人一样
Eben, like so many around the world,
正趴在他家客厅的地毯上玩乐高积木
is sprawled on his living room floor playing with LEGO bricks.
这是我们所期待的 对吗
This is what we expect, right?
毕竟 世界上约有五亿的人口是在乐高积木的陪伴下长大的
After all, around half a billion people grew up with LEGO bricks.
在这星球上 每个人可拥有超过100块的乐高积木
There are over 100 LEGO pieces for every person on the planet.
但是这个故事 但是 你在那能听到我吗
But this story... but... Can you hear me out there?
哇 这样好多了
There. That's better.
咋了 出了什么问题
What? What's wrong?
你为什么那样看着我  噢 噢
Why are you looking at me like that? Oh, oh.
这样吧 如何啦
There. How's that?
现在 我知道 我知道
Now, I know. I know.
你认识我 对吗
You recognize me, right?
没有特色却很实用的手
Featureless yet functional hands.
可更换的头发
Interchangeable hair.
完美的金色 呃 或者棕黄色吧 我猜
Perfect golden, uh, tan, I guess?
但是这个故事并不是关于我的 呃 至少不是全部
But this story's not about me. Well, not entirely.
这个故事是关于一种简单的玩具
This story is about a simple toy that became,
呃 但它后来却不仅仅是个玩具
well, more than a toy.
在创造力的新纪元 它独一无二的特性是如何
And how its unique properties ushered in a new era of creativity,
成为不仅仅是孩童 而是整整一代人的指引者
not just for kids, but for a whole generation.
这不仅仅是关于积木
This is about more than the brick.
它超越了--不 等一下
This is beyond the-- No, hang on a second.
乐高积木纪录片
超越了积木  一部乐高积木纪录片
Beyond the brick! A LEGO Brickumentary!
噢 看呐 真是酷炫
Ooh, look at that. That's awesome.
在纽约市一年一度的玩具展览会
At the annual Toy Fair in New York City,
全球的玩具制造商聚到一起来炫耀
the world's toy manufacturers gather to show off
那些为孩子打造的他们所希望成为的大产品
what they hope will be big products for kids.
乐高 让我们直说
LEGO is, let's face it,
主席 全球玩具专家
无疑是玩具工业中最出色的成功传奇
undoubtedly the greatest success story of the toy industry.
他们已成为世界第二大玩具公司
They have become the number two toy company
只推出一类简单的玩具 那就是建筑
with simply one category of toy, and that's construction.
玩具内幕妈妈
它与美泰和孩之宝这样的玩具巨头相抗衡
And that's up against giants like Mattel and Hasbro.
美泰有风火轮  还有芭比娃娃
Mattel has Hot Wheels. They have Barbie.
孩之宝有"特种部队"人偶玩具 还有其他产品
Hasbro has GI Joe. And they've got other lines.
但乐高公司只有乐高积木
And LEGO just has LEGO.
当其他玩具公司看待乐高时
When other toy companies look at LEGO,
编辑 《开玩了》杂志
他们讲它看作一个强大的集团
they look at them as a powerhouse.
当你看待一个价值四十亿美元的品牌
When you look at a four billion dollar brand
并且今年还将持续增长的品牌
and that's going to continue to grow this year,
就会惊讶他们的成就
it's amazing what they've done.
它已经成为玩具界的巨人品牌
It's become a monster brand of the toy business.
那么乐高公司是如何取得形成如此大的规模呢
So how did the LEGO company become so huge?
我可以解释 不过我想最好先把这部分搁置不提
I can explain that, but I think I better park this thing first.
认识这个宝贝吗
Recognize this baby?
是啊 优秀的老型号 编号497
Yeah, good old number 497.
星际开发者
Galaxy Explorer.
它有这些很酷的黄色小窗
It had these cool yellow-tinted windows,
所有这些2x2的计算机操作台积木
all these 2x2 computer bricks,
还有 呃 这些东西
and, uh, these things.
它只是一个乐高品牌魅力历史的一小部分
It's just a small part of the LEGO brand's fascinating history.
让我们用一点时间 来个小小启蒙导读 关于这款玩具的发轫
Let's take a moment for a little primer on how the toy began.
噢 不 等一下
Oh, no, wait a second.
开始吧 这样好多了
There we go. Much better.
很多人把丹麦
Many people know Denmark
视为待组装家具的故乡
as the home of ready-to-assemble furniture.
可悲的是 这些人错了 因为那是瑞典
Sadly, those people are wrong because that's Sweden.
丹麦是汉斯·克里斯汀·安徒生
Denmark is home to Hans Christian Andersen,
美味的甜点的故乡
delicious pastries,
和正如你会猜到的 乐高积木的出生地
and the birthplace of, you guessed it, LEGO bricks.
追溯至1916 一个叫欧拉·克里克·克里斯琴的丹麦人
Back in 1916, a Danish man by the name of Ole Kirk Christiansen
住在丹麦一座古色古香的小镇 比隆
lived in the quaint little town of Billund, Denmark.
是个做生意的木匠
A carpenter by trade, he started
他开的一家小的木屋商店在一场火灾中被夷为平地
a small wood shop which burned to the ground.
不是个很好的开端
Not a great start, but Ole
但欧拉并未退缩 又开了另外一家
would not be dissuaded, so he built another one.
在新的工厂里 他有了做搭建玩具的灵感
In the new factory, he was inspired to build toys.
到二十世纪三十年代
By the 1930s, Ole was
欧拉以他用桦木制作的拉拔式玩具而出名
known for his pull toys made from birch wood.
卡车 火车 当然还有鸭子
Trucks, trains, and of course ducks.
也就大约在这个时候 欧拉想出了乐高这个名字
It was around this time that Ole came up with the name LEGO.
它来自丹麦语短语leg godt 意为"好玩"
It comes from the Danish phrase leg godt, meaning "Play well."
然后这工厂再次被大火夷为平地
Then the factory burned down again.
但在欧拉的坚持下 它再次重建了
But with Ole's perseverance, it was rebuilt again,
这回最主要生产木制玩具
this time mostly for making wooden toys,
直到1947年的重大日子到来 欧拉去参观一个玩具市场
until a fateful day in 1947, when Ole was visiting a toy fair.
他遇到了一个新型装置 一个塑料模型机器
He came across a new contraption, a plastic molding machine.
欧拉带回了丹麦的第一台塑料模型机器
Ole brought the first one back to Denmark,
尽管不是所有人对它深刻印象
though not everyone was impressed.
起先 欧拉用他的手动模型机器
At first, Ole used his hand-powered molding machine
来制作简单的塑料玩具
to make simple plastic toys.
但后来他的儿子高梵想了一个很棒的点子
But then his son Godtfred had a brilliant idea.
我记得我父亲 对他来说
I remember my father, for him,
这个装置非常非常重要
the system was very, very important,
因为能把积木变成一套可玩的系统
to turn the bricks into a system of play.
老板 乐高集团
积木本身当然也是一个简单的结构
The brick in itself is, of course, a simple structure.
但用有限的积木 却能有无数的可能
But with the number of bricks, you have endless possibilities.
这个主意保留了下来 乐高玩具装置就此诞生
The idea stuck, and the LEGO system of play was born
并延续至今日
and continues to this day.
事实上 1955年制造的乐高积木
In fact, bricks made in
跟你在今天能买到的积木依然可以配套使用
1955 still work with bricks you can buy today.
积木的堆叠效果还不错
The bricks were great for stacking,
但仍有改进空间
but still had room for improvement.
克里斯琴的解决办法是改善抓合力
The Christiansen solution was clutch power.
什么是抓合力
What is clutch power?
抓合力就是用于把积木组合到一起的
Clutch power is the result of the patented studs and tubes design
钉纽和管状结构专利设计
that holds the bricks together.
也能让它们
And allows them to...
咻
...whew...
分开
come apart.
然后在1960年 这家工厂再次失火了
Then in 1960, the factory burned down again.
是~的~ 无论如何 它们到底是用什么建的这些工厂啊
Yeesh. What are they building these factories out of, anyway?
但是欧拉不管那讨厌的火灾 又回到了工作
But Ole went back to work, and despite those pesky fires,
他的公司继续发展壮大
his company continued to grow.
这个神奇的构件能够把相连接的积木
This magic formula of an ever-expanding system
无限扩大组合的一套装置 使得乐高玩具
with its locking bricks made LEGO toys
成为了吸引世界各地孩子们的神器
something that appealed to kids everywhere.
当一个丹麦人的努力成为了全球现象时 开启了什么呢
What started as a Danish endeavor became a global phenomenon.
公司继续发展壮大
Helping with this expansion of the company
是在其长孙凯尔的帮助下 你之前见过
was oldest grandson Kjeld, who you met before.
你可能在最早版本的包装盒上认出他
You might recognize him from some of the earliest boxes.
可爱的小帅哥
Cute kid.
就个人而言 我觉得凯尔在乐高的历史上做出的最大贡献
Personally, I feel Kjeld's greatest contribution to LEGO history
是他在乐高迷你人偶的发展中所扮演的角色
was his role in the development of LEGO minifigures, or minifigs.
嘿 伙计们 还没胳膊呢 哈?
Hey, guys, still no arms, huh?
几年下来 他们显然经过了设计上的改进
They obviously improved on that design over the years.
但真正让公司赢得更大成功的
But what really catapulted the company into greater success
是新的主题套装 比如城堡和太空
were the new theme sets, like Castle and Space.
后来是  授权主题比如星球大战
And later, licensed themes like Star Wars.
嘿 还有哈利波特
Hey! And Harry Potter.
哇 哇
Whoa, whoa.
哇 呀
Whoa! Yikes!
今天的乐高公司每分钟可生产超过十万件积木
Today the LEGO company makes more than 100, 000 pieces a minute,
已经成为世界上最大的玩具公司
and has become one of the biggest toy companies in the world.
但在其一路发展的过程中
But not without first experiencing some serious challenges
在重新定义自己方面仍要首次经历重大挑战
in having to redefine itself along the way.
我们稍后再说这个问题
But we'll get into that later.
只是想 所有这些
And just think, all this
来自于丹麦比隆的一个不起眼的木匠
from a humble carpenter in Billund, Denmark.
哦 抱歉
Ooh, sorry.
大概是因为没有抓合力 我想
No clutch power, I guess.
比隆依然是乐高公司的核心
Billund is still the heart of the LEGO company,
乐高迷你人偶仍然在这里制造
and LEGO minifigures are still made here.
英俊的小恶魔们 不是吗
Handsome little devils, aren't they?
好吧 那个镜头着实吓到了我
Okay, that shot kinda freaks me out.
比隆也是乐高设计团队的故乡
Billund is also home to the LEGO design team.
在这里 设计间内 未来的乐高套装
Here, inside the design room, the LEGO sets of tomorrow
正在现在被我们的设计师所构想着
are being dreamed up today by designers.
每个我遇到的员工都说
Everybody I meet says
乐高设计师
我有这世界上最酷的工作之一
that I have one of the coolest jobs in the world.
能创造这些积木真是太有意思了
It's fantastic to be able to create with these bricks.
乐高设计师
我们的书桌永远摆满了乐高积木
We have our desks full of LEGO all the time.
好像我这辈子余下的时光都能当个孩子
It's like being a child for the rest of my life.
对很多人来说 搭建乐高积木时
For many, the only limitation
唯一的局限是你的想象力
of building with LEGO bricks is your imagination.
但对于乐高公司的设计师们来说
But for the designers at the LEGO company,
这是一个要严密得多的过程
it's a much more regimented process.
乐高设计师
我们一直在这些乐高积木的体系内
We're always working within a system based on
进行创造工作
these LEGO bricks here.
其可能性并不是无穷无尽的
There's not an infinite amount of possibility.
如果你愿意 这些限制也可以成为挑战
The constraints becomes the challenge, if you will.
乐高设计师
后来 正是这些限制给了我们
Then it's those constraints that are interesting
找到奏效方案的有趣灵感
to find how do we make it work.
你不得不去思考孩子们怎样玩乐高
You have to think about how kids play with LEGO,
乐高设计师
这也是我们脑中一直在设想的
which is something that we always have in our minds.
如果你今年五岁 那用这些小积木搭建东西
If you're five years old, it's a lot harder to build
要比对一个八岁的孩子来说难得多
with smaller bricks than it is for an eight-year-old.
设计流程中的核心是一个指导性的原则
At the core of the design process is one guiding principal.
设计的流程真正开始于
The design process really
宇宙中的一个故事
starts with an idea of a story in a universe.
我们真正地把这些人物作为切入点
We really take a starting point in who these characters are,
他们住在哪儿 他们做些什么
where they're living, what they're doing.
故事提供给你做事的背景
Story provides context for what you're doing.
它给你和孩子们一个特定的意义
It gives you and kids especially a meaning.
某种意义上它帮助他们以全新的方式展开想象力
It sort of helps to unlock their imagination in new ways.
我们就是试图
We were just trying to put
将我们从未用过的颜色组合搭配在一起
together color combinations we haven't done before.
詹米·贝拉尔德是公司里的设计明星之一
Jamie Berard is one of the company's design stars.
他是专业建筑物系列的创意领队
He's the creative lead for the expert building series.
今天他正在给他的上司展示他新的巴黎式小餐馆的模型
Today he's showing his boss his new Parisian cafe model
这模型即将公开面世
which will be revealed to the public soon.
我在乐高积木展上最希望出彩的是讲述故事场景
What I really hope to highlight at BrickCon is the storytelling.
举个例子 这个阳台上的男士
For example, the gentleman on the balcony
其实准备了一个小惊喜
has actually got a little bit of a surprise,
手里拿着一个戒指
and he's got this ring in his hand.
那会帮助他顺利地和女友结为连理
That will help him hopefully marry his girlfriend.
这份工作 实在是太赞了
The job, it's amazing.
乐高设计师
我并不想过分吹嘘 你知道
I don't want to oversell it that, you know,
周二有数不清的巧克力牛奶以及按摩福利
there's rivers of chocolate milk and massages on Tuesdays.
你知道 这是一份工作 但它是一份太棒的工作
You know, it's a job. But it's an amazing job.
你可能会好奇 例如 它能持续多久
You almost wonder, like, how long can this last?
这是真的吗
Is this for real?
恩菲尔德 康涅狄格州
另一份在乐高公司让人梦寐以求的工作
Another coveted job at
是搭建专家
the LEGO company is that of master builder.
像设计师一样 搭建专家们
Like the designers, master builders are, well,
对于搭建乐高积木非常精通
masters at building with LEGO bricks.
但他们要想的是包装盒以外的东西
But they get to think outside the box.
所以作为一个搭建专家
So as a master builder, we get
模型展示设计师
我们要做出能制成我们模型的任何东西
to do everything it takes to make our models,
我们要设计模型 我们会做一个很好的组合体
we design models, we do a pretty good mixture.
每件作品都是从微小的模型做起
We do everything from little tiny models,
搭建人物也是如此
all the way up to human beings.
它总会是与众不同的
It's always going to be different.
每个模型的姿势都是挑战
Every model poses its own challenge.
有时是模型的庞大的体积
Sometimes it's the sheer size of the models.
最终 在最后的一天结束
Ultimately, at the end of the day,
你真的就是做到了能用乐高所做的极限
it's really just pushing the bounds of what you can do with LEGO,
有创造力 有艺术性 还有所有这些惊人的作品
being creative and being artistic and all these amazing things.
今天 搭建大师们在致力于一个庞大的工程
Today, the master builders are working on a huge project
将会被全世界所观赏
that'll be seen all over the world:
那就是为乐高电影的布景
the setting for The LEGO Movie.
为乐高工作最好的事情就是
The nicest thing about working for LEGO is that
我们有我们所需要的全部构件
we have all of the pieces we need.
乐高搭建专家
这是绝大多数人梦寐以求的
It's something that most people would just dream of.
在这座特殊的乐高城里  我就这么坐下来
For this particular city, I got to sit down and
定购任何我想要的东西
order whatever I wanted.
至于电影的情节
As far as the plot of the movie,
我真的不知道太多
I really don't know a lot about it.
唔  其实有很多东西
Um, there's a lot more than
远不止是电影里即将上演的
just this that's going to be in this movie,
我们在同一时间里努力着
that we're all working on at the same time.
这是一份有纪念意义的事业
And it's a monumental undertaking.
几周后 他们的乐高城抵达了
Weeks later, their LEGO city arrives
然后被保罗的团队在洛杉矶的摄影棚中重新组合
and is reassembled by Paul's team on a soundstage in Los Angeles.
它作为现场拍摄的序列布景
It serves as the setting for the live action sequences
在威尔·法瑞尔的地下室里
in Will Ferrell's basement.
好了 请无关人员离场
Okay, clearing guys, please.
开拍
Action.
是啊 这有些疯狂 我们已经
Yeah, it's been kind of crazy, we've had, uh,
我们拍摄实景电影已经五天了
we're shooting for five days of live action
这部电影基本是动画的
and the movie's mostly animated.
我们搭建了滑稽的乐高模型作为背景
And we've built this ridiculous LEGO model back there.
乐高电影编剧/导演
我们自己搭建了它
We built it ourselves.
亲自地 只用我们的双手
Personally, with our bare hands.
事实上 我们有一个超级的搭建能手团队
Actually, we had a team of super master builders.
它看起来非常出色
And it turned out pretty awesome.
非常喜剧化
It's pretty ridiculous.
这些人在康涅狄格州为此已经忙碌了
These guys have been working on it in Connecticut
大概 三个月了
for, like, three months.
然后 当然 我们做的第一件事是来
And then, of course, the first thing we do is go,
好吧 我们要推倒所有这些
okay, we're going to smash all of this.
所以 这是座城 是某种意义上的城堡世界
So there's a city, there's sort of a castle world
我们称它为中西兰岛
that we're calling Middle Zealand.
那有一艘海盗船
There's a pirate ship.
一些经典的太空的东西来自79年的系列
Some classic space stuff from '79.
听说我们会得到一些免费的乐高玩具
We heard we would get some free LEGOs.
耶 我在一块一块地组装一架经典宇宙船
Yeah! I'm literally doing this for one classic space ship.
嘿 菲尔  你的人给我的人打电话
Hey, Phil, have your people call my people,
我们搭伙吧 一起吃午饭怎么样
we'll hook you up. Maybe we can do lunch?
这部电影的布置给人印象非常深刻
So, this movie set is pretty impressive.
但是捷克的搭建专家
But the master builders in the Czech Republic
在致力于一个甚至更大的工程
are working on even bigger things.
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h乐高工厂
克拉德诺 捷克共和国
在克拉德诺(捷克地名) 我们为乐高乐土主题公园
In Kladno, we produce big models
和乐高市场在制造大型模型
for LEGOLAND parks and for LEGO markets.
我们有好多不同的东西可以做
There's a lot of different stuff we can do.
人们不知道的是 我们有计算机程序
What people don't know is we have computer programs
产品经理 乐高公司
在模型搭建者观察图层的部分
where model builders see the layers.
并非每块积木都是可视的
There is not visible every single brick.
内部还有钢质结构的部分
There is steel construction inside.
我们期待着至今我们所建造的最大工程
We are looking forward to the biggest project we've ever built.
这是保密的 应该没有人知道这个项目
It's secret. Nobody should know about the project.
就是那里 这是交界面
So there, this is the interface.
和亚罗米尔一起为秘密建筑工作的
Working with Jaromir on the secret build
美国项目经理戴尔·切斯
is American project manager Dale Chasse.
好吧 所以我们要把所有这些东西从毫米换算成英寸
Okay, so we'll convert all this stuff from millimeters to inches.
现在我的手头有着最有意思的工程
I have the most interesting project on my plate right now,
项目主管 乐高公司
比我和乐高公司合作了21年以来
than I've had in the whole
所有的项目都更有趣
21 years that I've been with the LEGO company.
我们在秘密地设计
We're secretly designing
和搭建一个真实大小的X翼星战战机
and building an X-Wing fighter, life size.
而这个项目真正酷的地方在于
But what's really cool about this project is
我们在复制一个其实你可以在商店里买到的我们的产品
we're copying one of our sets that you can actually buy in store.
这其实是它的构件序号 9493
It's actually the item number, 9493.
你可以自己在家里组装一个
And you can build this set at home.
而我们做到的是建造一个比它大42倍的模型
But what we've done is we've built it 42 times bigger than this.
这将会成为有史以来搭建的最大的乐高模型
This is going to be the biggest LEGO model ever built.
我们甚至无法相信这会成为现实
Even we can't believe this will be a reality.
我们有个庞大的团队
We have a big team here.
这是设计者 这是技术开发员
There is a designer, there is technical developer,
那是模型搭建者和机械师的团队
and there is team of model builders and mechanics.
我们工作程序的开始就是设计
The beginning of our process is design.
然后是技术开发
Then in technical development,
这是关于设计内部钢质结构的部分
it's about designing internal steel construction.
我们面前有很多挑战
We have a lot of challenges in front of us.
我们没有太多的时间分给每个单一的步骤
We don't have much time for every single step.
它将会用掉八吨的乐高积木
There will be eight tons of bricks used.
因此他们必须为我们
So they have to produce the
在比隆接连生产好几周的积木
bricks for us for a couple weeks in Billund.
太疯狂了
It's crazy.
X翼战机从机翼尖端到尖端的距离是44英尺
The X-Wing is 44 feet from wing tip to wing tip.
从头到尾有45英尺
It's 45 feet from bow to stern.
有11英尺高
It's 11 feet tall.
重44000磅
It weighs 44,000 pounds.
花费一万七千个小时用于建造
And took 17,000 hours to build.
最终 这个X翼战机模型准备好要跨越大西洋了
Finally, the X-Wing model is ready to cross the Atlantic,
在那里将继续它的冒险
where its adventure will continue.
但我们等会儿再回到这个故事
But we'll get back to that later.
我要把这些积木挨个捡起来
I'm gonna pick up the pieces
搭建一个乐高房子
And build a LEGO house
如果事情搞糟 我们能将它推倒
If things go wrong we can knock it down
乐高绝对是我童年的一部分 它是 嗯
LEGO was definitely part of my childhood, it was, uh...
艾德·希兰
格莱美提名歌手/作曲者
我和我哥哥有一个大盒子装着所有的东西
Me and my brother had a big box filled with everything,
是从我父母那里传下来的
um, just passed down from my parents.
但更多的是零碎的块 而非成套的模型
But it was more of the blocks rather than the sets.
任何时候我们组装一套
And any time we'd get a set,
它都挺像那些小东西的其中一个
it would be like one of the small ones.
而你永远都在盯着一套大的
And you'd always look at the big kits
在商店里可能就像这样 噢 我想要那个
in the shops and be like, "Oh, I want that."
然后只要有钱进账 我就像这样
And as soon as I came into money, I was like,
我要买什么呢 房子 不 车子 不 乐高
"What should I buy? House? Nah. Car? Nah. LEGO."
我的专辑一周内销量超五十万 然后我想要想法儿来庆祝一下
My album went gold in a week, and I wanted a way to celebrate.
我买的第一个东西就是死亡星际的乐高模型
The first thing that I bought was the Death Star.
它能做到的最主要的一件事是
The main thing that it does is it,
为你带回来一部分你的童年
it brings out a bit of your childhood.
而能够不忘记童年是很重要的
Which is important not to forget as well.
你明白  能让生活不那么严肃是件好事情
You know, it's good not to take life too seriously.
长大后 乐高对我来说更像这个
Growing up, LEGOs was more like this to me.
它更像一个 你知道 一个充满乱码的二进制文件
It was more, you know, the bin of chaos.
我就觉得  噢 不 谁会 为什么你要让乐高积木们知道
I was like, "Oh, no, who would-- why would you get LEGOs
《南方公园》创作人
要它们会被怎样组到一起呢
to be told how to put them together?"
就像 我总是认为它是一个非常有创意的东西
Like, I always thought it was a very creative thing.
然后我 我想我在南方公园大概制作到第二或第三季时
And then I, I think I rediscovered LEGOs
重新找到了乐高
right around the second or third season of South Park.
身边的人不会常相伴 喧嚣始终上演
People would walk in while chaos was going on,
我则会 只是把这些东西组合到一起
and I'd just be putting together these things.
而且我想 就像说明手册中介绍的那样
And I think that having that instruction book that said,
这一个在那一个的上面 然后这一个在那一个上面
this one on top of that one. And this one on that one.
对我来说这真是太治愈系了
It was just so therapeutic for me
因为我生命接下来的部分就是
because the rest of my life was,
想出一些东西 想出一些东西
think of something, think of something.
你知道 保持创意 保持创意 保持创意
You know, be creative, be creative, be creative.
然后我发现它是如此疯狂地有益身心
And I found it so insanely therapeutic.
回到篮下
...goes to the basket!
我其实玩很多不同的游戏
I've actually been on the road to a lot of different games.
粉丝可能就像这样说 伙计 我跟你一样爱乐高积木
And the fans are like, "Man, I love LEGOs just like you, man."
美国职业篮球联赛球员
我家里至少有三十盒乐高
I have at least 30 boxes
等着我开始去拼
that are waiting at home for me to start working on.
我拥有的最大的一件乐高
The biggest piece that I have is actually the piece
是艾伦·德杰尼勒斯(著名同性恋主持人)给我的
that was given to me by Ellen DeGeneres.
我们告诉我们在乐高工作的朋友们说你喜欢乐高
We told our friends at LEGOs that you love LEGOs.
-嗯哼  -所以我们为你准备了点东西
- Mm-hmm. - So we got you something.
等一下
Wait a second.
有没有任何家伙在你看来就像孩子一样
Did any of those guys look like kids to you?
似乎乐高的粉丝有很多不同的类型
It seems like LEGO fans come in many forms.
让我们来见识其中的一些吧
Let's go meet some of these, um,
我不太确定你怎么称呼他们
well, I'm not sure what you call them.
我们去看看吧
Let's go find out.
嘿  有谁能把我的头发扔回来吗
Hey! Can somebody just throw my hair back up here?
在西雅图的乐高积木展 你可以看到
Here at BrickCon in Seattle, you can see part
与乐高一同成长的庞大群体
of the huge community that's building with LEGO bricks.
乐高积木展是北美最顶端的乐高展会之一
BrickCon is one of North America's top LEGO conventions,
与芝加哥的乐高世界和弗吉尼亚的乐高展览会齐名
along with Chicago's BrickWorld and Virginia's BrickFair.
还有类似的粉丝盛会
And there are similar fan events
遍布欧洲 亚洲以及全球其他地方
throughout Europe, Asia, and around the globe.
花费一点时间在任何一个展会
Spending a little time at one of these conventions
都会使你领略到乐高领域的广大
gives you an idea of the vastness of the LEGO universe.
展会里有人玩乐高
There are those that use LEGO,
还有一个成人粉丝团体
and there is an adult fan community.
我们自称为AFOL
We all refer to ourselves as AFOLs, absolutely.
一个成人乐高粉
An Adult Fan Of LEGO.
这也是我们在这的原因
Which is basically, the reason we're all here.
对于我来说 成为粉丝中的一员意味着
To me, being one is just enjoying everything
享受乐高的一切
about what LEGO's about.
你知道辛普森一家里的漫画男吗
You know the Comic Book Guy from The Simpsons?
那就是我认为的别人眼中的乐高成人粉丝形象
That's I think what people think an AFOL is.
就是一个大男人住在父母的地下室
Just a big guy living in his parents' basement.
成天都在敲电脑键盘
Just kinda tapping at the computer all day long.
如果那不是一个成人乐高粉丝又是什么
Well, if that's not an AFOL, what is?
蓝领 白领 程序员 建筑师
Blue collar, white collar. Programmers, construction guys.
教师 高管
Schoolteachers. Executives.
科技行业的人
People working in science and industry.
技术宅 陌生人 怪胎  像我这样的人
Geeks, strangers, weirdoes. People like me.
我就是个技术宅
I am totally a geek.
对我来说 这就是一年一次
For me, this is the class reunion
与最好朋友们的班级聚会
with all your best friends, once a year.
AFOL绝对是个社团
AFOLs are definitely a community. Very much so.
感谢互联网使这一切成真
And thank you, Internet, for making that happen.
我上网的时候
It was a kind of a light bulb,
就像发现了新大陆
when I go on the Internet, and I'm like,
"哇 还有其他人也喜欢玩乐高"
"Wow, there's other people that like doing this."
乐高社区有着自己的语言
The LEGO community does have its own language,
是由使用的首字母缩写词定义
and it's defined by the acronyms that it uses.
AFOL代表乐高成人粉丝
An AFOL is an Adult Fan Of LEGO.
与之相反的是KFOL 代表乐高儿童粉丝
As opposed to KFOL, which is Kid Fan Of LEGO.
TFOL代表乐高青少年粉丝
TFOL, which is Teen Fans Of LEGOs.
有些人用NLSO
Some people use the term NLSO,
代表乐高成人粉丝的非乐高迷配偶
which stands for Non LEGO Significant Other.
MOC代表我自己的创作
MOC. Which means My Own Creation.
LUG是乐高玩家团体
A LUG is a LEGO Users' Group.
LTC  乐高火车俱乐部
LTC. LEGO Train Club.
GBC  超级运球装置
GBC. Great Ball Contraption.
SNOT就是积木颗粒不朝上
SNOT would be Studs Not On Top.
还有POOP 意思是别的零件上的零件
There's POOP. Parts Out of Other Parts.
CRAPP是破坑烂板，少有人喜欢的组件
CRAPP is a Crummy Ramp And Pit Plate.
BURP  又大又丑的岩石状组件
BURP. Big Ugly Rock Piece.
还有声名狼藉的LURP
And the infamous LURP.
意思是又小又丑的岩石状组件
The Little Ugly Rock Piece.
他们甚至有自己的货币
They even have their own currency.
这是一个黑色 1x2的砖
It's a black, 1 x2 brick.
你可以花3、4 分钱买一个
You can buy these for three, four cents apiece.
但这种白色的砖
But this piece produced in white,
上一次厂家制造是80年代中期
the last time they made it was the mid '80s.
正如一个股票市场有着供应和需求
Just like a stock market would be, supply and demand.
你想要买的话就要花4或5美元
And you wanna go buy it, you're gonna spend $4 or $5 for it.
所以乐高公司是怎么看待这些的呢
So what does the LEGO company make of all of this?
我们有点吃惊
We were kind of shocked.
这一切是基于用户想要做的
This is all based on what they want to do.
也是他们想要构建的
It's things they want to make.
这是他们想要组织的活动
It's events they want to organize.
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h高级主管
乐高社区活动参与
我们完全没计划过那些情况
We hadn't planned that.
这是超过我们所控制的
It's out of our control.
相扑大战
速度比赛
划船比赛
袋子中建模
完成
Done!
2 1 开始
Two, one, start.
盲建
在这里  我找到了
There it is. I found it.
-不  不是那个  -不 绝对是
- No, no. That's not it. - No, it's definitely it.
很多会展上
A familiar face at many
出现的一张熟悉的面孔是乐高设计师詹米·贝拉尔德
conventions is LEGO Designer Jamie Berard.
记得他吗
Remember him?
杰米在乐高的职业生涯是以一名乐高粉开始的
Jamie's LEGO career started as an AFOL.
我当时在一家玩具店
I was just at a toy store,
我看见很多成人聚集在乐高产品的过道旁
and I see all these adults in the LEGO aisle.
我当时想 这真奇怪
And I'm thinking, this is a bit odd.
因为我平常都是等到孩子们都走了
'Cause I'm used to normally waiting until the kids leave
才过去快速地瞥一眼
and then I can come over and take a quick peek
假装是给别人买
and pretend I'm shopping for someone.
这些人在那里聊天
These guys are hanging out talking,
各自炫耀他们的乐高套装
and they're showing off the sets,
然后一个套装买五份
and they're buying five copies of a set.
我当时想 我也会这么做!
And I'm like, I do that!
你们是干什么的  你们是谁
What do you... Who are you guys?
然后他们说 "我们有个俱乐部  你想来参加吗"
And they said, "Yeah, we have a club. Would you like to join?"
所以那真是一个很酷的时刻
And so it was actually this really cool moment where I...
我根本不知道它的存在 然而它找到了我
I didn't even know it was there and then it kind of found me.
杰米的生活在凯尔·克里斯汀安森和
Jamie's life changed when Kjeld Kristiansen
其他乐高高管们参观一次会展上看到了他的作品后发生了变化
and other LEGO executives visited a convention and saw his work.
所有的乐高高层们同时在一个地方出现
All these LEGO people that I never imagined I'd ever meet
这是我从来不敢想象的
were all in one place at one time,
当他们看到我建造的建筑物时
and saw all the stuff I was building
就来和我谈话
and started having a conversation with me,
问一些奇怪的问题
asking curious questions like,
比如"你有没有想过在海外工作"
"Have you ever thought of working overseas?"
然后他给我他的名片
And then he hands me his business card
然后说 "我很乐意继续这场谈话
and says, "I'd like to continue this conversation
在我回到丹麦后"
when I get back to Denmark."
接着他真的这么做了 我拿到了实习机会
And then... he did, and I got an internship,
然后我拿到了这份工作
and then I got the job.
我认为去乐高盛会是一件很酷的事情
I think it's awesome when I go to the LEGO events
产品设计经理
建造师
产品&市场研发部门
因为在很多程度上有些事情并没有变
because, in many ways, some things haven't changed at all.
我任然保持那份好奇心
I still have that curiosity.
我等不及去看大家的作品
I just can't wait to see what everybody's built,
去见到那些熟悉的面孔 那些和我一起玩的人
to see the old faces, people that I've hung out with.
这很有趣  大家看到我都是发自内心的快乐
It's just fun. People seem genuinely happy to see me.
我也很热爱的一个事实是
And I love the fact that
我还能感觉到自己是社团的一员
I still feel like I'm part of the community.
我是个彻彻底底的乐高成人粉  我不喜欢一些称呼
I'm a complete AFOL. I hate the term, because, like,
比如星舰迷和神秘博士迷能起这些酷酷的名字
Trekkies and Whovians get these cool handles.
乐高成人粉丝
而我们只用首字母略缩词
We have to use an acronym.
我建造来自大荧屏和小荧屏
I build characters from the big screen and the small screen,
电动游戏和网络文化里的角色
from video games and from Internet culture and memes.
我第一个作品是史蒂芬·霍金模型
The first one was my Stephen Hawking model,
这个模型出乎意料地火了
which unexpectedly went viral.
那时我才意识到
And that's when I realized
乐高创作有着更多的受众
there was a larger audience for LEGO creations.
我很期待和我的乐高好友们
I'm most looking forward
重聚一堂
to connecting with all my LEGO buddies again.
我们将会看到所有我们创造的
Uh, we get to see all the new things
新的作品  这是一场表演
that we've created. It's putting on a show.
对于像我这样的书呆子
And for a nerd like me,
你不是经常能有这样展示的机会
it's not often you get a chance to put on a show.
所以你想好要去乐高积木展带什么了吗
So, did you figure out what you're bringing to BrickCon?
想好了 我会带闹鬼的玩偶之家
Yeah, I think I'm going to bring the Haunted Doll House.
我们俩都像小孩一样迷乐高
We both were into LEGO as kids.
我们谈恋爱的时候并没有意识到
We didn't realize it when we started dating.
直到我们结婚搬到一起
And when we got married and moved into the house,
戴夫的妈妈打电话说 "过来拿你的东西"
Dave's mom called and said, "Come get your stuff."
在那堆东西中 我们发现了一大浴缸的乐高
In that stuff, we found a huge tub of LEGO.
我们一天晚上坐下来开始建造
We sat down one evening and started building.
我们一起玩然后
So, yeah, we did that and
发现俩人一起玩乐高好玩多了
found out it was a lot of fun to build together.
-没错  -我们真的很享受
- Yeah. - And we really enjoyed it.
我趋向于建很多蒸汽朋克的东西
I tend to build a lot of steampunk creations.
我喜欢蒸汽朋克的典雅
I just like the elegance of steampunk.
我趋向于关注小细节和内饰
I tend to focus more on the small details and interiors.
你也很热衷迷你人
You're also really big on minifigs.
没错 我是很喜欢
Yes. I do like minifigs.
很明显我们得把那辆车拆下来
Well, obviously we're gonna have to take the car down.
乐高会展上的大玩笑是1x5
The big joke at LEGO conventions is the 1x5.
呃 对于你们不了解1x5是什么的人
And uh, for those of you that don't know what a 1 x5 is...
那是在乐高社区对于一个漂亮女孩的代号
That is a guy code in the LEGO community for a hot girl.
因为乐高不制造1x5的砖块
And, it's because LEGO doesn't make a 1x5.
很多年前 出现在会展上的漂亮女孩是稀有物
Years ago, hot girls at conventions were a rarity.
但是 我很幸运有了自己的1x5 所以我满足了
But, you know, luckily I have my 1x5, so I'm all good.
我对于玩乐高的成人的解读是他们只是高个儿儿童
My definition of adults that play with LEGOs are just tall kids.
我喜欢建造 但我不是最好的建造者
I like to build, but I'm not the best builder.
你知道谁是最好的建造者吗
Do you wanna know who the best builder is?
我妈妈
My mom.
我在搭建最后几棵桦树马上完工
I'm finishing up just the last few of the birch trees
在图书馆的后面
here behind the library.
这棵在瑞文戴尔中间
And, uh, it's in the middle of Rivendell.
我们很兴奋这个即将完工
And we're really excited about finishing it,
但我们也有点吃惊
but we're also a little
它最后完工的样子真的好大
bit surprised at how big it turned out to be.
当你在每次只拼凑一个部分时
You never quite know when
你不会了解成品会有多震撼
you're working on one section at a time,
直到你把所有部件拼到一起
until you put it all together.
我几年前才开始重新玩乐高
I just started building again a couple years ago
那时我儿子对乐高积木表示有兴趣
when my son was getting interested in building.
我们就弄两节长吧
Let's make it only two segments long.
为什么
Why?
我们不想让它太宽
Because we don't want it to be too wide,
因为这个紧挨着岩石
'cause it's up next to rocks.
我从在家洗衣服的家庭主妇变成
I went from doing laundry one day
网络相簿上有超过两百五十万点击量的博主
to having over two and a half million hits on my Flickr pages.
这其实挺让人喘不过气的
And it was pretty overwhelming.
连续两年 Alice的作品都获得
For two years in a row, Alice's work has received
由会展访客评选的令人梦寐以求的人民选择奖
the coveted People's Choice Award from convention goers.
今年她建造的是一个瑞文戴尔的大型模型
This year she's built an enormous model of Rivendell,
来自电影指环王里的虚构城市
the mythic city from The Lord of the Rings.
我认为大家会喜欢的
I think people are going to like it.
我认为不会有相似的模型出现在会展
I don't think that there's anything quite like it.
我最喜欢做的事情之一是在会展上
One of my favorite things to do in a convention is
鼓励女孩们来玩乐高
to encourage the girls to build.
乐高一直是把焦点放在男孩身上
LEGO has historically really been focused on boys.
他们也承认自己
And they have admitted they
只面向一半的人口
have only been addressing half the population.
乐高现在认真对待这个问题了
They're now taking it seriously.
我认为目前还有很多未开发的
I think there's a tremendous world of possibilities
超多的可能性
that has been untapped so far.
有很多女孩走到我面前说
There are lots of girls who come up and say,
"谢谢你树立一个榜样"
"Thank you for being a role model."
拉起吊桥
Raise the drawbridge!
装载上飞牛弹弓
Load the "Cattle-pults"!
放出猎犬
Release the hounds!
哦 你们好
Oh! Hi, guys.
正如你所见
As you can see, people
人们用乐高砖块建造出各种各样的东西
build all sorts of things out of LEGO bricks.
人们想出的组合几乎是无穷无尽的
The combinations people come up with, it's almost infinite.
等一下 我想知道是不是无限的  嘿
Wait a minute, I wonder if it is infinite. Hey!
在丹麦有一个人想要解决这个问题
There's a guy in Denmark trying to figure that out.
我要谈论一些关于乐高排列的
I'm going to talk about things that we know about
数字增长的事情
the growth of the number of LEGO configurations.
我叫索伦· 艾勒斯我是一名数学教授
My name is Soren Eilers. I'm a professor of mathematics.
数学系
哥本哈根大学 丹麦
一切都起始于乐高乐园
It all started in LEGOLAND, actually.
那是丹麦夏天雨季的一天
It was one of those rainy days in Danish summer,
我和我的女儿在一起
and I was there with my daughter.
索伦看到一个展品展示了
Soren saw a display dedicated to the original patent
由奥勒的儿子戈弗雷申请的原始专利
filed by Ole's son, Godtfred.
戈弗雷被专利局问到
Godtfred was asked by the patent officer,
"你能有多少种拼起六块砖块的方法"
"How many ways can you put together six of these bricks?"
然后他说 大概是 我们还在研究
And he says, something like, "We're still working on it,
但是当我出门的时候 我们已经算出102,981,000种 这种话
but when I left home, we had 102,981,000,"
反正就是这意思吧
or something like that.
所以我开始好奇他们怎么计算出这个数字的
And so I was wondering how they computed that number
因为看起来这是一个数学难题
because it seemed to be a difficult mathematical problem.
乐高做的只是数叠罗汉
What LEGO had done was to just count the-- the towers
就是把砖块叠起来
where you put the things on top of each other.
然而如果我有个建筑是有点矮而宽的
Whereas if I have a building that is sort of low and wide,
我最终有很多选择
I have a lot of options for the final one.
当然我有试着用理论推翻
Of course I tried to attack this with theory,
但是我没有任何进展
but I didn't get anywhere.
本质上 我能想到
So, essentially, all that
能做的就是求助计算机
I could think of doing was ask a computer.
事实上我的程序非常的低效率
In fact my program was very inefficient.
花了我一周才算出这个数字
Took me a week to compute this number.
正确的数字相当的大
The correct number is quite a lot higher.
正确答案是915,103,765
The correct number is 915, 103,765.
但是一旦索伦算出了结果 一个显而易见的问题是
But once Soren had the number, the obvious question was,
如果你加第七块砖块呢
what happens if you add a seventh brick?
或者第八块
Or an eighth?
算到五很容易
So it's pretty easy to count all the way to five.
六的话 我可以在五分钟内验算这个数字
Six, I can now recompute this number maybe in five minutes or so.
然后每次要花一百倍以上
And then each time it takes about a hundred times more.
下一次是几小时
So, next time it's a couple of hours.
算到八花了我将近五百小时
Counting eight it took me something like 500 hours.
如果我要算九或是十
So if I was to count with nine or ten...
可能要花费数年 也许数百年
This would probably take years, maybe hundreds of years.
这个未解的问题能说明关于乐高系统的什么呢
So what does this unsolvable problem say about the LEGO system?
用数学来定义就是它是个有限的系统
By mathematical definition, this is a finite system.
砖块的数量是有限的
We have a finite number of bricks.
螺柱和小洞的数字是有限的
They have a finite number of studs and holes.
但对于有实际目的的人们来说
But for all practical human purposes,
这些砖块却是无限灵活的
these bricks are infinitely flexible,
不仅这样 他们定义了
and not only that, they define
一个无限复杂的数学问题
a mathematical problem of infinite complexity.
我会说
So I would say that,
"是的 组合是有限的 但某种程度上也是无限的"
"Yes, it is finite, but in a way it's also infinite."
我认为这是我们称作为
I think this is the beginning
系统创作力的开始
of what we call systematic creativity.
乐高这种把管子和螺柱组合在一起的基础系统
This basic system of tubes and studs that locks together,
乐高设计师
能展现一个孩子的或是一个成人的想法
and it will take a child's idea or an adult's idea,
还能把这些想法都聚在一起
and it'll hold it together.
让这些想法成形 给他们新的交流方式
It'll give it form and give them a new medium of communication.
关于乐高砖块的有趣的是 我们可以看到
The interesting thing with the LEGO brick, as we see here,
高级主管 乐高未来实验室
讲解砖块怎么互相搭配的说明书
is that the instructions for how it fits with the rest
实际上是潜移默化的
is actually embedded.
我们不需要说明书
We don't need an instruction.
我们不需要一本字典或是语法
We don't need a dictionary or grammar.
这是系统自带的
It's embedded in the system.
他变成了一个让
It became this platform
全世界的人共享一种语言的平台
where people all over the world had a shared language,
就像音乐中的谱子或音符
it's like the letters or notes in music.
乐高是一个创造性的工具
It's a creative tool,
它是一个创造媒介
it's a creative medium,
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h高级主管
乐高社区活动参与
但也是一种语言
but it's also a language.
但是一种比英语和Windows
It's a language that's more global
更全球化的语言
than English and Windows.
有这么一个无限制的产品
So with such a limitless product,
乐高公司是怎样
how did the LEGO company
不断获得成功的呢
experience anything but constant success?
信不信由你 不久之前
Believe it or not, not that long ago,
乐高陷入可怕的困境
the company was in pretty dire straits.
在CBS电视台的全球市场观望节目
On the CBS Worldwide Market Watch,
丹麦玩具制造商乐高
the Danish toymaker LEGO
CBS 晚间新闻 5月11,1999
今天报告它的首次年度亏损
today reported its first ever annual loss.
如果孩子喜欢 为什么
If the kids love it, why
丹麦总公司陷入这么多麻烦
then is the Danish company in so much trouble?
乐高所遭受的是公司在1978年
What happened to LEGO is LEGO had an unprecedented growth rate
首席执行官 乐高集团
获得玩具生产权以来都以史无前例的增长率增长
when it really got the bricks right in '78,
直到1990年中期
until the mid-1990s.
市场增长的很快 一切都很好
It was growing fast, everything was good,
突然就坍塌了
and it suddenly collapsed.
三大产品中的两个销售额跌落的很惨
Sales of two of their three big products fall off a cliff.
\h\h\h\h\h\h\h\h管理学教授
沃顿商学院
2003年几乎要破产
And they almost went out of business in 2003.
执行副总裁 乐高公司
10年前 我们的公司陷入严重的问题
Ten years ago, our company was in serious trouble,
而巧妙的的是 我们不能责怪任何人
and the wonderful thing about it, we couldn't blame anybody else.
他们失去了最重要的资产前景
They had lost sight of their most important asset:
那就是乐高系统的天才之处
the genius of the LEGO system.
来自世界各地的聪明的人在90年代告诉乐高
Smart people from around the world had told LEGO in the '90s
这些砖块会变得不那么好玩儿了
that this brick is gonna become irrelevant.
你需要另辟新径
You need to find new things.
这些看起来 实际上 已经不那么酷了
It was seen as-- Actually, this was seen as uncool.
乐高开始生产越来越多的定制特别套装
They were making more and more custom pieces for specific sets.
一方面来说 他们有超过14,000个独特部件
At one point, they had over 14, 000 unique elements.
而有些套装只有
Some of the sets had only a
很少的部件 且几乎并不需要动手组装
few elements and required almost no construction.
当我们制造易于构建的产品
When we made products which were quicker to build,
那些不喜欢建造的仍然说
those who didn't like to build still said,
"我不喜欢玩乐高
"I don't like to build it.
我宁愿买模型车或者玩偶什么的"
I'd rather buy a die-cast car or doll or something else."
真正喜欢乐高的人
And those who actually did like LEGO for what it is,
会说 "现在是怎样"
they said, "What is this now?"
因为我们不了解
And because we didn't understand that
坦白讲 我们其实
and also because we were actually, frankly,
作为一个公司面对我们的顾客相当自大
quite arrogant as a company towards our customers,
我们在生产错误的产品
we were making the wrong products,
我们甚至没法把产品递送到
and we were not even able to deliver the products
真正想在商店买的人手里
that people wanted to the stores.
乐高的粉丝知道错在哪里
Their fans knew what was wrong,
但是乐高高管没有
but LEGO company executives weren't paying attention
注意到玩家社区已经遍地都是了
to the community that had grown around their product.
改革的萌芽在几年前发布一款叫做Mindstorms
The seed of change had been planted a few years earlier
的机器人系列时就种下了
with the release of a product called Mindstorms.
这个小的黄色砖由乐高和麻省理工开发
This little yellow brick, developed by LEGO and MIT,
使乐高创造品变成可互动的机器人
turns LEGO creations into interactive robots.
对我们而言这是一次很棒的机会
For us this was a great opportunity,
学习研究教授 麻省理工
因为我们看到把乐高和计算机结合在一起的潜力
'cause we saw a great potential of combining LEGO and computers.
乐高有开发的打算
LEGO had in mind that they would develop it,
技术创新教授 麻省理工
然后孩子们可以按规定的方式玩机器人
and then kids would play with it in the prescribed way,
他们有孩子作为受众
and they had as an audience children,
即乐高标准的 传统的受众
their standard, traditional audience.
但是它是有点
But it really sort of
捕获到各个年龄的想象力
captured the imagination of people of all ages,
而不是像最初
not just the young people
只为年轻人设计的那样
that Mindstorms was initially intended for.
事实上 机器人系列推出的第一年
In fact, in the first year that Mindstorms came out,
一半的销售额是卖给成年人的
half of the sales were to adults for adult use.
有一个在斯坦福的人
Then there was someone who
喜欢乐高 他说
liked LEGO who was at Stanford and was like,
"嗯 这个砖块
"Hmm, this brick, I could
我可以黑了它然后写一个逆向程序"
hack that open and reverse engineer it."
他们拿机器人系列开刀
And they were opening up the Mindstorms.
他们为这个系列写新的软件
They were writing new software for it.
三个月内 一千个黑客在研究这个
Within three months, a thousand hackers were working on it.
对乐高而言很震惊
And this was rather a shock for them.
他们的回应是 "这是什么"
LEGO's response was pretty much like, "What is this?"
他们在拆开我们建造的成果
They're taking apart what we created.
我是说 我们把这些结合在一起 所以不能被分开
I mean, we put this together, so it shouldn't be taken apart.
那是我们的秘密
That's our secrets.
我们的管理层有很多问题
There was a lot of questions in our leadership.
我们可以要么
We could either take the
激进的 防御的控制路线
aggressive and protective and controlling route,
要么其他的路线说
and the other route would be to say well,
这个有意思
this is, uh, interesting.
大多数公司里 传统的创新方式是
In most companies, and also in a very traditional way
对创新严格机密
of innovating was to have it super-secret.
就好比标着X的封闭墙壁
It's like closed walls, sign on the "X,"
我们什么都不能说
And we couldn't say anything.
我们和律师有很多内部讨论
We had a lot of internal discussions with our lawyers,
高级主管也有涉及
top management was involved.
凯尔不得不站起来说 "但是我想要这个
Kjeld had to stand up and say, "But I want this.
我们公司生产的产品 是人们可以拿来创造东西的
We're a company who makes things that people can create with."
当一个公司开始和用户打交道
When a company starts to deal with users,
然后发现可以在用户身上找到灵感
and discovers that it can get ideas from users,
这就是乐高智力风暴机器人系列
that's Mindstorms.
这是用一种新的方式来说
That's the new way of saying,
你需要和你的乐高成人粉打交道
you will deal with your Adult Fans Of LEGO,
你会从他们身上获得有益的想法
and you will get from them useful ideas.
我们需要意识到
We need to be aware
世界上最聪明的人中有99.99%
that 99.99%
都不为我们工作
of the smartest people in the world don't work for us.
在头脑风暴系列产品发布后
In the wake of the Mindstorms product release,
乐高公司开始以更开放的态度
the LEGO company was more open to ideas
吸纳设计室以外的灵感和想法
that came from outside the walls of its design room.
芝加哥建筑师亚当里德
Adam Reed TuckerChicago Architect Adam Reed
用乐高积木建造了摩天大楼
Tucker builds skyscrapers out of LEGO bricks
在2005年他的公司在金融危机下倒闭
In 2005, when his firm went belly-up from the economy,
亚当决定通过建造建筑模型
Adam decided to return to the more artistic side
重返更加有艺术美感的领域
of architecture by creating architectural models.
有一天 当我走出家门 走进了一家当地玩具店
One day I ventured out to a local toy store
店里摆满了装着乐高积木套装的购物车
and filled about a dozen shopping carts of LEGO sets
我想以这种方式重新熟悉砖瓦
to get reacquainted with the brick.
当我回到家后 我把这些积木倒了出来
And when I got home, I dumped out all these sets,
这时候我的未婚妻来了
and my fiancée came home,
她看到我坐在那儿
and she saw me sitting there
她便扭头走了
and she made a U-turn.
一小时后 她打电话给我问道
Then an hour later, called me and said,
有什么事儿是我需要知道的吗
"Is there something I need to know?"
亚当的作品很快吸引了
Adam's work soon caught the
乐高公司的帕普·史密斯-迈耶的注意力
attention of the LEGO company's Paal Smith-Meyer.
我产生了一个想法 与那些对我们所做事情
And I had this idea that let's start new business with people
抱有极大热情的人开展一项新的业务
who have a passionate feeling about what we do.
于是我去见了亚当
And then I meet Adam and he's standing there
他与自己用乐高积木组建的超高建筑物站在一起
with these super tall structures built out of LEGO.
然后我就 哇塞他们太棒了
And I'm like, "Wow! These are amazing.
我们可以做一整套产品线 但是我作为乐高的内部员工
We can do a whole line but me coming from the inside,
我需要证据 我需要实实在在的物证
I need evidence, you know, I need proof.
所以我们能向世界证明这个想法行得通
So we can prove to the world that this works.
两个月以后 我来到积木世界
Two months later, I come to BrickWorld and Adam says,
亚当说我有个惊喜给你
"I have a surprise for you."
亚当创造了第一套产品200盒
And then he's created 200 boxes of the first set.
亚当自己设计了盒子图样
On his own, Adam had designed the box graphics
并打包了每一套积木
and had packaged every single set.
如果亚当和帕普能成功制作建筑系列产品
If Adam and Paal could make the architecture series happen,
那结果也是可以令人信服的
it would take some convincing.
毕竟亚当向乐高玩具公司的提议
After all, what Adam was proposing to a toy company
实际上并不仅仅是一个玩具
wasn't exactly a toy,
迄今为止所有的乐高设计都出自乐高专用设计师之手
and up until now LEGO designs were only made by LEGO designers.
如果他当时没有坚持并且努力推动这个项目
If he hadn't taken and been so pushy,
今天的乐高建筑恐怕不会存在
architecture as it is today probably wouldn't happen.
这个系列是一个巨大的成功
The series was a success,
从那时起这个产品线也一直在不断扩张
and the line has been expanding ever since.
所以 这证明了我们可以和设计室以外的独立个人进行合作
So, it proved that we can work with individuals on the outside.
这个举动不会打垮乐高
It's not going to break LEGO.
事实上他们创造能量
It's actually creating energy.
他们创造希望
It's creating kind of this hope,
让我们去做更多的事情
uh, that we can make more things.
亚当现在正在开展新的工作 不断突破乐高的界线
Adam is now working on a new venture to push the LEGO boundaries.
在我做乐高建筑产品之后
Following up on what I did with the LEGO architecture,
我希望能为乐高创造一组过山车玩具
I wanted to create a roller coaster for LEGO.
我总是在想要推进产品线
I'm always about pushing the lines.
为了使过山车运作
To make the roller coaster work,
亚当在他的工作室里设计了两个新的元素
Adam designed two new elements in his workshop:
一个连接着铁轨的球状体
a ball joint attached to a rail tie,
还有一个套住球的环
and a hitch to mount the ball in.
他们创造了新的元素这件事
The fact that they do create new elements,
给了我一些希望
um, gives me hope that, you know,
这些元素也都是可以被创造的
these elements can also be created.
十天后 亚当在积木世界向帕普
Ten days later, Adam unveils his coaster prototype
展示了他的过山车雏形
for Paal at BrickWorld.
他非常的细致 非常棒
It's so smooth. It's amazing. Whee!
所以这就更像科幻小说里的那样
So, that's more of like um, a sci-fi kind of use.
这块像是一个赚到失控的煤矿
This one is a runaway coal mine.
是的 或者是银矿 是的
- Yeah. - Or silver mine. Yeah.
这在以前是不可能的
This would not have been possible before.
这看起来可能是一个过山车的零部件
It might look like a roller coaster part,
但是 你可以用它做你想做的任何东西
but hey, you can use it for anything you want.
我觉得这很棒
I think it's amazing.
我是说 我真的是这么想的
I mean, I definitely think that, you know,
世界各地的孩子们和成年人都会想要玩这个的
kids, adults all over the world will want to play with this.
每一个人  谢谢兄弟
- Everyone. - Thanks, buddy.
东京 日本
在东京 日本 康平西山
In Tokyo, Japan, Kohei Nishiyama
帮助打开了乐高社区的创意之门
has helped open the doors to creativity from the LEGO community.
他是一个做人群创意的专家 他管他的项目叫Cuusoo
He's an expert in crowd creation and calls his project Cuusoo,
也就是梦想或者愿望的意思
which means "Dream" Or "Wish."
康平和帕普合作创建了一个平台
Kohei worked with Paal to create a platform
能使乐高玩家的梦想成真
that brings LEGO users' dreams to reality.
乐高Cuusoo的创意在于让世界上的任何一个
The idea for LEGO Cuusoo is that anyone in the world
拥有乐高创意的人都能许愿让乐高有一天
who has a LEGO idea can "Wish"
把你的创意变成实实在在的玩具
That LEGO will one day make this.
你唯一需要做的事情就是在Cuusoo平台上
The only thing you have to do is actually share it
把你的创意分享出来
with the world on the Cuusoo platform,
并且通过这个平台
and through that,
创造一个围绕你愿望展开的有趣社区
create a community of interest around your wish.
那些得到10000个或更多乐高玩家支持的设计
Designs that gain support from 10,000 or more LEGO users
将被上报给乐高管理层
go up for review with LEGO management.
对于个人设计被乐高官方做成真实的玩具来说
It's quite an honor for a
这真是莫大的荣耀
design to get released as an official LEGO set.
第一个得到10000张选票的是乐高我的微观世界系列
The first idea that got 10,000 votes was LEGO Minecraft.
这只花了48小时
Took 48 hours.
这甚至让我们的服务器几度瘫痪
It broke our servers several times.
我想对于乐高粉来说
I think it's safe to say that LEGO fans
等待一个像康平的创意产生是一件肯定的事
were waiting for an idea like Kohei's to come along.
现在入围Cuusoo第五号套装
Now the finalists are being reviewed
的最终候选人都在被复审
for Cuusoo set number five.
华盛顿特区
如果这就是极客做的事儿的话
If this is what it is to be a geek,
我是百分百没意见的
I am definitely okay with that
因为 这是我经历过最有趣的事儿
'cause, uh, it's the most fun I've ever had.
Cuusoo不严格地翻译可以是指 愿望
"Cuusoo" Loosely translated means a wish.
我的愿望是看到更多的空间探索
And uh, my wish is to see more space exploration.
我希望人们能对宇宙空间探索更感兴趣
I want people to be more interested in space exploration.
我甚至从小学那会就知道
I knew even from elementary school
我长大了想成为一名机械工程师
that I wanted to be a mechanical engineer when I grew up.
问题是 中学里并没有
The trouble is, there were no
机械工程师的课程
mechanical engineering classes in middle school.
所以我想用乐高设计
So uh, I would design entire manned missions
一整套飞往木星执行载人飞行任务的机器
to Jupiter using LEGO designs.
大学毕业后 斯蒂芬找到了他的第一份工程师工作
After college, Stephen landed his first engineering job,
为NASA制作航天器
working on a space vehicle for NASA,
研制好奇号火星车
the Mars Curiosity Rover.
我在无尘间里度过了大量的时间
I spent a lot of time in clean rooms
围绕真正的漫游者零件开展工作
working around parts of the actual rover itself.
这是我最想做的事
It was all I could ever want to do.
这是一个巨大的 7英尺高 2000磅的
It's a huge, seven-foot-tall, 2,000-pound,
核动力 岩石钻探
nuclear-powered, rock-drilling,
激光爆破 科学操作的机器人
laser-blasting, science-performing robot.
最初我只想建造一个漫游者
Originally I just wanted to build a rover so I could,
这样我就可以向我的朋友和家人展示我到底在做什么样的工作
you know, show my friends and family what I was working on
还有这项工作有多酷 别人都不知道
and how cool it was before anyone else even knew about it.
这个是偏离差速器摇臂转向架悬挂系统
This is the off-set differential , rocker bogey suspension system.
在顶端这里是 偏离差速器手臂
And on top here is the uh, off-set differential arm
在漫游者顶端摆动
that swings across the top of the rover,
他连接悬挂系统的左边和右边
and it connects the left and right sides of the suspension system
这样的设计使得漫游者在不平的地表
that allows the rover to keep all six wheels on the ground
也能六个轮子都着地行走
as it travels over uneven terrain.
这并不是要与火星人打仗或者什么的
It doesn't have to be, you know, battling Martians or anything.
做这些都是为了科学
It's doing it all for science.
我不是一个很外向的人
I'm not a very outgoing person,
我以前不是经常
and I didn't always, uh,
和很多乐高玩家互动
interact with a lot of LEGO users before.
我有我自己的私人收藏
I just had my own personal collection.
但是我喜欢那种你如何剪断自己脐带
And I like how you can disconnect the umbilical
从自己封闭的世界走出来的感觉
and take the capsule off...
我参加了我的第一场乐高玩家大会
I went to my very first uh, LEGO Users Group meeting,
叫做 LUG
called uh, a LUG.
好奇号火星车收到了很多好评
And uh, the Curiosity Rover was received very well.
每个人都觉得他棒极了
Everyone thought it was awesome.
事实上他们都说 嘿 你应该把这个作品上传到Cuusoo上
In fact they said, "Hey, you should submit this model to Cuusoo."
当然啦 我心里的孩童想
And of course, the kid in me thought,
哇我也可以做一名乐高设计师 这简直太棒
"Oh, wow, I could be a LEGO designer. "That's awesome."
看着这个作品我给他投了票
Looking at it and I voted for it,
最开始的话只有 好像几百张票吧
and there was only, like, a few hundred votes.
之后一周内我又去看了一下
Then within a week I looked at it again.
事情一下子变得不一样了
It started going up all of a sudden, I went,
等下 这是斯蒂芬的作品 简直太酷了
"Wait a minute, that's Stephen's. This is cool!"
我对其他参赛者的作品有一点了解
I know a little bit about the other contestants,
其中一个绝对是
and one of them would definitely be
乐高公司制作的最大的乐高套装
the largest LEGO set that LEGO has ever produced
如果他们确实把他变成了一个积木套装的话
if they actually did turn it into a set.
瑞士
这花费了我大约9个月去完成
Took me about nine months to complete it.
当然 这不仅仅是一个建筑 这是一项研究
It's not just building, of course. It's research.
我得找齐所有的模型图片和所有零部件
I had to find all the pictures for the model and all the parts.
不到最后我根本无法确定他能否被完成
I wasn't sure until the end if it's going to work
还有驾驶时的重量问题 但是很幸运我都做到了
and drive because of the weight, but I was lucky with that.
这并不仅仅是威信的问题
It's not just about prestige.
如果最终的设计被选中了
If the finalists' designs are chosen,
他们会从销售纯利中得到1%的分红
they'll get 1% of the net sales.
如果我赢了 我会把他建造成比原来大一倍的样子
If I win, then I will build it twice this size
并且在沙漠中驾驶它
and ride on it through the desert.
奥克兰 新西兰
之后他会一直不停的继续开
It will just keep going round and round.
今年Cuusoo项目的第三个决赛选手
The third finalist in this year's Cuusoo project
是一个新西兰的尼克 沃什领导的乐高玩家俱乐部
is a user group led by New Zealander Nick Vás.
尼克和他的团队用乐高积木
Nick and his team have created LEGO models
创造了电子游戏 传送门2
of the video game Portal 2,
这个游戏非常受乐高玩家的喜爱
which is very popular with the LEGO crowd.
我们决定让传送门成为我们Cuusoo项目的主题
We had decided on Portal as the topic for our Cuusoo project,
就是因为我们都对乐高和portoal
simply because we had a common love for LEGO
这款电子游戏都同样有爱
and Portal as a video game.
传送门项目是其中最快达到
The Portal Project was one of the fastest ever to reach
被考虑为Cuusoo网站上入围决赛的
the necessary 10,000 votes to be considered
必要条件 10000票这个要求的设计
a finalist on the Cuusoo website.
我们认为我们的项目是最能脱颖而出的
We think that our project is the most likely.
我们对胜出抱有很大的希望
We're holding high hopes that it will be us.
我为他们投了票 因为我玩这个游戏
I voted for them, 'cause I played the game,
而且我也乐在其中
and I really enjoyed it.
同样 我也希望那一个也能被选中
And I was... I'm hoping that one could be chosen, too.
我一定会买很多套这款积木的
I would definitely buy multiple copies of that set.
所以如果这项产品投入生产了
So if the product goes to design,
你打算用得到的钱做什么
what are you going to do with all the money?
如果我能想做什么就做什么的话
If I could do whatever I wanted with it,
我想我肯定还会去买乐高的
I think it would probably all go right back to LEGO.
所以基本上来讲你是为了积木去做这件事的
So basically you're doing it for the brick.
是的 很对
Yeah, pretty much.
我认为Cuusoo最有趣
I think the interesting thing,
也许也是最可怕的事情
and then maybe the scary thing with Cuusoo,
就是他真正的开放了公司
is that it has actually opened the company,
他真的几乎完全把公司内外颠倒了
it has actually almost turned it inside out.
之前的运营模式 你知道
What happened before with, you know, this,
所有的设计都是秘密 都在封闭的院墙之内
everything happened in secret, behind closed walls,
而现在一切颠倒了
is now reversed.
他现在给全世界创造了一件激动人心的事
It's created an excitement in the world that we can,
就是我们可以一起塑造乐高产品的未来
together, shape the future of LEGO products.
几个月的考察后 乐高代表将会揭露
After months of review, LEGO representatives are ready to reveal
这三个最终入围决赛的设计
which of the three finalists
到底哪一个会被选为Cuusoo套装005号
will be chosen as Cuusoo set number 005.
你们大家激动吗
Are you guys excited?
这将是你们见到的下一个Cuusoo模型
This is the next Cuusoo model that you're gonna see.
冠军是
The winner...
好奇号火星车
the Mars Curiosity Rover.
无论我幻想了多少次这个场景
No matter how much I fantasized about it,
还是无法和我听到梦想实现的时候相比
it couldn't prepare me for the reality of the actual news.
我百感交集
I have all sorts of emotions and feelings running through me.
很难尝试着去形容这些感觉
It's hard to try and describe how they all feel
当这些感觉混合起来的时候
when they're mushed together like that.
乐高社区的创意
Innovation from the LEGO community
并不是一定需要乐高公司的参与
doesn't necessarily need to have the LEGO company's involvement.
当乐高公司对外界的创新者
While the LEGO company is more and more open
越来越开放
to innovators from the outside,
还有一些人希望能为自己定制一套乐高
there are others who are customizing on their own.
在西雅图 华盛顿
In Seattle, Washington,
威尔·查普曼围绕着乐高产品的生产线
Will Chapman has built a successful business
的一个漏洞经营着一份成功的生意
around a hole in the LEGO product line.
这是一款M2勃朗宁机枪
This is an M2 machine gun.
这是一款二战时期MP40德国机关枪
This is the MP40 German machine gun from World War II.
我自己的大口径狙击步枪
My HCSR.
他的生意是制作人仔规模的枪
His business manufactures minifigure-scaled guns.
他为什么会从事这个呢
Now, why would he do that?
乐高不会做我做的东西
LEGO will not produce what I produce.
老板 玩具制造公司
乐高不会做任何当代武器
LEGO won't do any weapons that are modern.
他们会做荒野西部 这大约是19世纪中期的事了
They'll do Wild West, which is maybe up to the mid-1800s.
之后我们做了一些后现代主义的东西 星球大战
And then we got postmodern, which is Star Wars.
武器不符合乐高"开心地玩"的哲学
Weapons don't fit into the LEGO "Play well" Philosophy.
我认为作为一家丹麦公司 枪支拥有权这个主意
I think being a Danish company, the idea of handgun ownership,
武器拥有并不是他们文化的一部分
weapon ownership is not a big part of their culture.
所以我说 不如我们自己来试试吧
So I said, "Let's try it ourselves."
当我设计了一个武器的时候
When I design a weapon,
我去网上找了一些能激发我灵感的照片
I look online for some inspirational photos.
人仔的问题是 他们的手太大了
The trouble with the minifigure is they have giant-- giant hands,
他们只是人类的缩小版
and they're a squashed-down representation of a human.
设计他们实在是太难了
They're really tough to try to design for.
这是艺术
It's art.
真的 我 相信这是艺术
It's truly, I believe it's art.
他们买来给军队装备的人
The folks that are buying to equip an army
总是成年人 然后他们会买几百把枪
are always adults, and they'll buy a hundred of one gun,
买200个头盔
they'll buy 200 of a helmet.
从一些只是全副武装的小人偶
It's gone from just a couple of figures armed with a weapon,
到组成场景 完整的战役 诺曼底登陆 诺曼底入侵
to scenes, entire battles, D-Day landing, Normandy Invasion.
也有费卢杰进攻
There's invasions of Fallujah,
也有现代海军 现代军队
there's modern military Marines, there's modern army.
你需要一把 这可是标志性武器M16
You need an M16. It's an iconic weapon.
这开始于一个兴趣 我从没想过
This started as a hobby, and I never thought
这会变成
that this would turn into
一个世界现象
something that could be a worldwide phenomenon.
乐高的世界顺应潮流 非常模块化
The LEGO world is so adaptable, it's so modular,
乐高不需要去做决定
that LEGO doesn't get to decide.
我们来决定我们想怎样运用这些元素
We get to decide how we want to build with those elements.
咔
Cut!
来吧伙计们 生动一点 你们太僵硬啦
Come on, guys, put some life into it. You're so stiff.
好 那我们就休息五分钟吧
Okay, let's just take five then.
外行
Amateurs.
好吧 我在哪儿 哦好的
All right, where was I... Oh, right.
旁白呢
Narrator guy!
好 乐高系统证实了玩儿是个很重要的事情
Okay, the LEGO system has proven it's a great thing for play,
但是他也能用在更严肃的事业上吗
but can it be used for more serious endeavors?
世界上有一些人将乐高用作工具
There's people around the world using LEGO as a tool
跟把他用作玩具一样 我们来看
as much as a toy. Cut to:
博伊西 爱荷华州
外部 远景 爱荷华州博伊西
Exterior. Establishing shot. Boise, Idaho.
我们在我妈的车库 我们正在制作一部电影《熔点》
We're in my mom's garage, and we're making my film Melting Point.
这是一部用乐高积木搭建的单格拍摄动画电影
It's a stop-motion animated film made with LEGO bricks.
乔纳森·沃恩和马特·科恩
Jonathan Vaughan and Matt
在洛杉矶一个电影学校相识
Cohen met at film school in Los Angeles,
他们都退学了 因为他们
but they both dropped out because they were frustrated
可以做的项目都受挫失败了
by the scale of projects they could do.
我以前觉得乐高积木就是给孩子玩的
I used to think that LEGOs were just for kids
直到我遇到了乔纳森
until I met Jonathan
并且从乐高电影社区得到了一个望远镜
and got a telescope into the LEGO brick filming community.
和积木电影一起 你是无拘无束没有限制的
With brick films, you're uninhibited.
如果他需要一个12英里的高速公路来开展一场射击汽车追逐
If he needs a 12-mile highway to shoot a car chase,
他只需建造一个12英里的高速公路
he builds the 12-mile highway.
无论他想到什么 他都可以建造出来 而且他做了
Whatever he thinks of, he builds it and he does it.
让人能走路 比如走5英尺
To get somebody to walk, like, five feet,
你需要15个框架来满足每一秒的步行场景
you have to take 15 frames every second of that walk.
所以你不得不非常仔细的移动他们
So you have to move them in just little millimeter increments.
这实在是太单调乏味了
It's incredibly tedious.
我从来没有做过这么耗费时间的事情
There's nothing else I've ever done that takes this long.
但是当你操作人仔的时候
But when you're working with minifigs,
你不需要在乎代理人或者自尊或者任何事
you don't have to deal with agents or egos, or anything
因为你在和非常有规范的演员合作
that befalls working with regular actors.
他们很棒
They're great.
如果我想一天做16小时 他们也不会抱怨
If I want to do a 16-hour day, they don't complain.
没有加班
No overtime.
乔纳森妈妈
乔纳森正为他的电影创造新的场景
Jonathan's creating one of his sets for his movie.
他们在车库里进行这项工作
They're doing the work in the garage.
他跟我说他正在制作一部电影 我必须对他有信心
He tells me he's making a movie. I have to take that on faith.
他正在玩儿乐高的玩具
He's playing with LEGOs,
这也是他从蹒跚学步的孩童时期就开始做的事
something that he's done since he was a toddler.
我的家人也很支持我
My family has been pretty supportive about this.
他非常有创造力
He's very creative,
但是我也非常想
but I would really like
我的车能重新停回车库
to be able to park my car in the garage, yes.
积木电影有很长的历史传统
Well, there's been a long tradition of brick films.
我最喜欢的积木电影制作人之一是大卫·帕加诺
One of my favorite brick film makers is David Pagano.
纽约的电影制作人大卫·帕加诺
New York filmmaker David Pagano
从他九岁起就开始制作积木电影
has been making brick films since he was nine.
大卫被认为是乐高顶级的动画片绘制者
David is considered one of the top LEGO animators,
而且因为用积木创造了复杂的角色而闻名
and is known for creating complex characters out of bricks.
你看的大多数电影
Most films you're going to
都会把人仔当成主要的演员
see will have minifigures as the main actor.
乐高电影制作者
因为他们足够灵活
They're just articulated enough to be
可以被做出各种有趣的造型
moveable into a variety of fun poses,
但是还没有灵活到你不用
but not so over-articulated that you need help
摆弄他们就可以恰当的站直的地步
getting them to stand up properly,
或者看起来像一个普通的人类
or look like a normal human being,
或者跟没有鼻子的人一样正常
or as normal as someone with no nose looks.
嘿
Hey!
我用人仔做了很多东西
I have done a lot of stuff with minifigures,
不仅为乐高也为我自己
both for LEGO and just for myself,
但是我就是没法
but I also am just endlessly
从用积木建造各种玩意儿的巨大吸引力中走出来
fascinated with what you can build from bricks.
我觉得比起现成的演员
I just find it an interesting challenge
用乐高玩具更有趣和挑战性
as opposed to having a readymade actor.
我宁愿找办法去做一个整洁的角色
I'd rather figure out ways to make neat-looking characters,
然后确保他们都能用动画的方式呈现
and then make sure they're animate-able,
之后再给他们生命
then bring them to life.
我有点像一个乐高的档案管理员
I am somewhat of a LEGO archivist.
开心的时候我觉得我是
On my better days I consider myself
乐高动画的历史学家 如果这样的工作存在的话
a LEGO animation historian, if such a job exists.
我并不认为他存在但是我会一直对自己假装
I don't think it does, but I'll pretend to myself,
直到别人叫我停止
until someone tells me to stop.
所以最初的乐高电影是宣传视频
So, the very first LEGO films were promotional videos
或者六七十年代制作的商业片
or commercials that were made in the '60s and '70s.
我认为中间一大部分
I think it should have a big middle part
和两边的电影脱颖而出了
and two little sides that stick out.
但是第一部粉丝电影直到
But the first fan film didn't come
20世纪80年代才面世
until the mid-to-late 1980s,
这个电影叫《魔法传送门》
and that was a film called The Magic Portal.
他们用很有趣的方式摆放斜块积木
They used sloped pieces in a really interesting way
你可以得到这些在积木套装上爬行
where you could get these weird little blobby creatures
的奇奇怪怪的斑点小生物
that crawl along the set.
这儿也有一些用老的乐高挖土机碎片
There's some nice animation
做的不错的动画片
with some of the old LEGO backhoe pieces.
在2000年 乐高公司真的开始起飞
In the early 2000s, LEGO films really started to take off.
每个人都有网络 而且这个看起来
Everyone had the Internet, and it was starting to become
并不会快速过时  这并不是一时的流行
this thing that was not going away, it wasn't a fad.
而是在每个人的家里
And it was in everybody's
这也作为一种连接人与人的方式
home as a way to connect with other people.
这是一种 我会称作是
That's sort of when I would say
乐高动画的摩登时代开启
"The modern era" Of LEGO animation started.
你可以在网上找到
The LEGO animation content
乐高动画的全部内容
that you can find online just runs the gamut.
这事很酷 这事也很奇怪
There's cool stuff, there's weird stuff.
有些东西放在一起真的很棒
There's some stuff that's really well put together
而且拍摄的也非常棒
and just shot gorgeously
而且每个部分的运用也非常有趣
and has really interesting parts usage.
当然也有很不合适的东西
There's immensely inappropriate stuff.
无论好坏你都可以得到
You can get all kinds.
还有一件变得很常见的事情是
One thing that's become pretty common
我们把有名的电影或者电影预告片的场景
is shot-for-shot remakes of scenes from famous films
一个一个镜头的重新制作
or film trailers.
所以他们会为你看到的每一帧电影制作不同的积木套装
So they'll build each set that you see in each shot...
描述一下玛瑟卢斯·华莱士是什么样的
Describe what Marsellus Wallace looks like!
什么  你再说一遍
- What? - Say what again!
我看过黑暗骑士
I've seen The Dark Knight.
如果在各方面都做到了极致
If you devote yourself to an ideal,
那就会升华到另一种境界
then you become something else entirely.
艾德·希兰有一支被授权
Ed Sheeran has a music video that someone was commissioned
乐高化的MV
to make into LEGO.
我要把这些积木挨个捡起来
I'm going to pick up the pieces
搭建一个乐高房子
And build a LEGO house
除了这个 人们还可以用乐高
Another thing that people are recreating with LEGO
重现盛事之景
is just, like, news events.
一些人试图重演奥运会
Some people were re-creating Olympic scenes,
从菲利克斯·保加拿(奥地利极限运动员)从空中起跳的那一刹那算起
and when Felix Baumgartner did that jump from space,
二十四小时后 这个场景就得以通过积木的形式再现出来
there was, like, a LEGO version of it, like, 24 hours later.
如果你在Youtube上搜索乐高
If you do a YouTube search for LEGO,
你会发现这个词至少有一千三百万的点击率
you're going to find 13 million hits at least.
我认为这种情况会变得更加普遍
I think it will only get more prevalent
也会有更多的人去推动它
and there will only be more and more people doing it
因为这实在是件有趣的事情
because it's super fun.
我的天 我喜欢这首歌
Oh, my gosh! I love this song!
这部乐高电影虽然是用电脑绘图制作的
The LEGO Movie was done with computer graphics,
但看上去却像是用积木搭建出来的
but made to look like a brick film.
导演特别点明
The director specifically said
他们是受到了乐高定格视频的启发
they were inspired by LEGO stop-motion web videos.
可以直接将素材转而用之 这真是再好不过了
And it's cool that they were able to include a few of those.
在这部电影的高潮部分
In the climax of The LEGO Movie,
你就可以看到我拍的清洁工那部分了
you can see my film Garbage Man.
哇 好赞
Whoa! Awesome!
它不是严格意义上的积木电影
It's technically not a
因为它毕竟还是电脑制作出来的
brick film because it's computer generated.
但我们的电影会全部按照积木电脑的流程来走
Ours is going to be fully stop motion,
所以我严密把关 就是为了确定这是个
so I'm trying to make one that's the best quality
有持久性的好模子
for a really long running time.
这将是乐高电影历史上的举世无双之作
It will be the greatest LEGO movie ever made.
如果不是 那我就失败了
Otherwise, I've failed.
在这部电影里 有一名警察
In the film, there's this cop,
一个一心只想当警察
who all he ever wanted to do was be a cop,
他叫托尼
this little LEGO guy named Tony.
他之前是个玩滑板的
And he used to be a skateboarder,
所以他可以踩着滑板追犯人
so he can chase criminals down on his skateboard.
然后这个人叫杜曼 超级无敌大反派
And then this guy Duman, this great classic super villain,
来到这座城市 纵火烧毁一切
comes into town and just starts burning everything down.
现在 为这无限的融化…
Right now, you're afraid...
而颤抖吧
of melting.
不出几秒 焦灼感就会吞噬
In a few seconds, you'll feel the burn
你那塑料做的小眼球
in your little, plastic eyeballs.
你是想要这种效果吗
Was that the direction you want to go?
嗯 我正在探索中 哇
- Yeah. I'm digging that. - Wow.
我一开始制作这部电影的时候
When I was originally working on the film,
并没有准备筹款
I wasn't planning to raise any money.
但是马特看过剧本之后
But then Matt looked at the script.
我就问 你接下来准备做什么
I was like, how are you going to do this?
你积木够吗
Do you have enough bricks?
这可比你之前做的任何一个决定都重大
This is way bigger than anything you've done that I've seen.
他说 "嗯
And he said, "Uh, well,
我们可能要用一些电脑图像界面来填补城市里的空白
we'll have to fill in the city probably with some CGI,
不过也可能需要多一点的积木"
maybe get a little bit more bricks."
然后我说 "不行
And I was like, "No.
你得用真材实料地建一个城市出来
You have to build a city.
这部电影必须是乐高史上的传世之作 乔纳森"
This has to be the greatest LEGO movie ever made, Jonathan."
所以我就回答他 “好吧 我们得把开头拍得牛一点"
And so I said, "Okay, we have to do a Kickstarter."
你好 我是乔纳森·沃恩 我正在导演《熔点》
Hi, I'm Jonathan Vaughan, and I'm directing Melting Point,
这是一部用乐高积木搭出来的分帧电影
which is a stop-motion animated film made with LEGO bricks.
我是罗伯特·弗利特饰演杜曼
I'm Robert Fleet. I'm playing Duman.
我要烧掉好多东西 特别好玩
I get to melt things a lot. It's really fun.
开始
Action.
大家听一下
So, guys, here's what I
这是我对现在拍好的镜头的一些想法
was thinking up for the establishing shot.
我们需要把这里的所有东西都建好
We're going to need to build basically everything you see here,
所以基本上来说 就是整个城市了
so pretty much the entire city.
那就是说我们要用电脑图像了?
We're going to have to use CGI, then?
不 不用
I will not use CGI, okay?
我要这个成为传世之作
I want this to be the best brick film ever made.
乐高是作为玩具被创造出来的 但现在 它就是…
LEGO started as a toy, but now it's definitely--
就是人们在他们这个古怪的爱好的世界里宣泄自己情感的方式
it's a way people are expressing themselves in this weird hobby,
所以它自然也是一种工具
so it's definitely also a tool
注定了要为了完成更重大的使命 注定了要讲述不平凡的故事
and a means to an end, a means to tell stories
也注定了要用更宏大的方式展现你自己
and express yourself in a gigantic variety of ways.
放眼世界 人们不断地在试图
All around the world, people are pushing the limits
在乐高这个世界里进行创新
of what they can do with the LEGO system,
试图开发出更新的建造材料
and what it's capable of as a building material.
现在我正式宣布 以一百一十二英尺
Now I can officially say, that with the height of 112 feet,
十一又四分之三英寸高度来看
11 and three-quarters inches,
你们现在已经成为吉尼斯世界纪录这个大家庭里的成员了
you are now members of the Guinness World Records family.
我现在要授予你这张证书 祝贺你们
I'd like to present this certificate and congratulate all of you.
-太棒了  -我们打破世界纪录了
- Yes! - We broke the record.
弥尔顿
在墨尔本史蒂夫·萨马蒂诺和劳尔·奥伊达
In Melbourne, Steve Sammartino and Raul Oaida
用乐高积木几乎做出了一整辆车
built a working car almost entirely out of LEGO bricks.
这辆车不会设定任何的速度记录
It's not going to set any land speed records,
当然 就算设定了也跑不到
and it doesn't go all that far,
但仅仅从能跑这方面来看 这辆积木车已经够厉害了
but just the mere fact that it does go is quite something.
安德鲁·卡罗尔是苹果公司的工程师
Andrew Carol, an engineer at Apple,
一直在研究一种古希腊的装置
studied the remnants of a
这套装置被发现于爱琴海底
Greek device used to determine celestial events,
是用来观测天文现象的
which was found at the bottom of the Aegean Sea.
他将这套装置重新改造了一下 毋庸置疑 用的是乐高积木
Then he reconstructed it from, you guessed it, LEGO bricks.
在乐高大会上 粉丝们齐聚一堂
At conventions, fans get
建立球模组
together to build great ball contraptions,
或者GBC GBC是用来在模块之间传递球的
or GBCs, which deliver balls from one module to another.
GBC是一尊动态雕塑
The GBC is a collaborative effort
它的形成是大家共同努力的结果
to make a kinetic sculpture, if you will.
在这里 如果你仔细观察 一旦球被碰击 就有两下反转
In this case, if you watch, when this ball hits, two flip off.
时间被精密地掌控好 所以这个门可以反转两次
And they're timed so that this gate double flips.
就连在谷歌工作的劳瑞·佩奇都在和乐高积木打交道
Even Google's Larry Page used LEGO bricks.
实话实说 在大学我就用乐高做了一台喷墨打印机出来
Actually, in college I built an inkjet printer out of LEGOs.
佩奇和谢尔盖·布林甚至
Page and Sergey Brin even
用乐高积木做出了他们的第一个服务器
built their first server out of LEGO bricks.
在英国 电视主持人詹姆斯·梅
In England, TV host James May
决定用积木建造他的工作室
decided to build an entire working house out of LEGO bricks.
所以 乐高的这个系统
So, the LEGO system can
可以让人们制作出有实用性的工具
enable people to make real, working stuff.
有时候 制作工具的过程是十分消耗脑细胞的
Sometimes, however, the goal is more cerebral.
纽约市
你觉得这个怎么样
What do you think that is?
是不是很棒
How great is that?
你要用你手机拍张照片吗
You going to take a picture with your cell phone?
老实说 我一开始没看到它 是我妹妹告诉我的
Well, I didn't see it at first. My sister pointed it out to me.
我是一名学前班老师 对乐高特别着迷
And I'm a preschool teacher, and I am drawn to LEGOs.
我是从印第安纳州来的 我们那里不常看到像乐高这样的东西
I'm from Indiana, we don't see things like that in Indiana.
这对于我来说很新奇
So, it's unusual.
人们是如此的熟悉乐高积木
People are so familiar with LEGO bricks.
基本上所有人都知道如何将积木拼插在一起
Most everyone you know has snapped a few bricks together,
所以 积木艺术是大众化的 和生活息息相关的
and so that makes the art accessible, it makes it relatable.
我第一次去美术馆的时候就说了
When I first started going to galleries and saying,
"嘿 我是搞乐高艺术的"
"Hey, I do LEGO art."
他们就看了看我然后说
They kind of looked at me and said,
艺术家
"哦是吗 是和车和城堡打交道吗?"
"Oh, okay, is that cars and trucks or castles?"
你懂的 他们对乐高艺术有种固定化的看法
You know, they have a set notion of what LEGO art would be.
我每个月都要订购上万块积木
I order tens of thousands of bricks every month.
就是这么疯狂 我就是这样收集积木的
This is how it is. This is how I get my bricks.
事实上 我每年都会用乐高拼六幅作品出来
In fact, I spend over six figures annually just on LEGO.
这就差不多用了这房间里的三百万块积木
There's probably 3 million bricks in this room.
我以儿童的玩具为业
I've made a career from a child's toy.
好多次有人和我说我这样有悖商业规则
I've been told at times I'm a sellout
因为我是在用一个品牌来塑造我的作品
because I use this commercial brand to create my art.
但我选了这个牌子 因为我相信
But it's a brand that I chose because I believe
有了它 我无所不能
there's nothing I can't build out of it.
我曾经买过很多的乐高积木作玩具
Growing up, I had a lot of LEGO bricks as a toy.
我父母也鼓励我这么做
It was something my parents encouraged.
他们在客厅里留出了一块三平米多的空间让我搭积木
They let me have a 36-square-foot LEGO city in our living room.
我十岁左右的时候 想养只狗
It was when I was about 10 years old, wanted to get a dog.
于是去问我父母 "我能养只狗吗"
Asked my parents, "Can I get a dog?"
"不 你不可以养狗"
"No, you're not getting a dog."
于是我捣毁了整个乐高城市
I tore down my LEGO city,
用那些积木拼出了一只真实尺寸的乐高狗
used those bricks to create my own life-size LEGO dog.
那是我第一次
It was really my first time in
意识到不是积木盒子上画着什么你就要照着拼出什么
realizing it's not what's on the front of the box.
你可以充分发挥创造力 拼出任何你想要的东西
You can actually create whatever you want out of this toy.
我从大学毕业之后
I got out of college,
社会压力很大 很难找到工作
and I had societal pressures to get a real job.
我最终去念了法学院 从事公司法
And I ended up going to law school. I was doing corporate law.
一天结束之后 我回到家
And I would come home at the end of the day
还可以有个宣泄创意的地方
and I would need a creative outlet.
有时候涂涂画画
And sometimes that was drawing, sometimes it was painting.
但我一旦开始积木雕塑
But once I started doing sculptures out of LEGO,
我就找到了自己的激情所在
I really had found my passion.
好像又回到了
And it got to the point
我在律所工作了一天的时候
where I was working full days at the law firm,
晚上我回到家
and I would come home at night
还有无数的工作还有繁重的工作等着我
and have a slate of commissions to work on.
我想要改变什么
And I decided to make that change,
放弃法律 去当一名艺术家
to leave the law practice behind, and go be an artist.
做一个和玩具厮混在一起的艺术家
An artist who plays with toys.
你懂的吧 我不知道…我是不是真的有了那个突破点
You know, I don't know if this is... if I've broken through.
我不知道一个艺术家
I don't know if an artist
会不会感受到那个突破点
ever can feel like they've broken through
因为我在不断地设置越来越高远的目标
because I keep setting bigger and bigger goals.
南森的眼前摆着一个绝无仅有的好机会
Nathan has been offered his biggest opportunity yet.
他在纽约的时代广场预约了一场个人展览
He's been booked for a one-man show in New York's Times Square
并为此准备了很久
and is prepping over a hundred pieces for it.
纽约展览会
The New York exhibition, I think,
这将是我人生里目前为止最重大的一次展出
will be the biggest show of my life,
是数年精粹的凝聚
a culmination of years' worth of work,
也是史上最大的一次乐高展示会
as well as the largest solo LEGO art exhibition ever.
压力自然很大
And there's a lot of pressure.
展出会重点突出南森自己的创意
The show will feature Nathan's original creations
也有一些他用乐高积木仿制的艺术巨作的展出
as well as LEGO replicas he is making of classical works of art.
对于南森来说 这是一个
For Nathan, this is the opportunity
证明自己是个真正艺术家的好机会
to prove himself as a legitimate artist.
我有点担心这个地点
I'm worried that the venue that's taking a big risk on me
会搞砸这场展出
feels like this is a failure.
我就是担心 观众们在这种形式下看到展出的时候
I'm worried that, you know, will they actually get it
还会不会体会到里面的精粹所在
when they see it in the exhibition format?
而且 公众们又会怎么想?
And really, what's the public going to think?
千里之外的德国 另一个艺术家简·弗门
Thousands of miles away in Germany, another artist, Jan Vormann,
带着他的乐高走上了街头
has taken LEGO arts to the streets.
我很喜欢带着那些已经在大家头脑中
I really like to work with objects
留下过深刻印象的东西一起玩
that everybody has a preconceived image of.
与有趣的东西一起工作的好处就是
The good thing with playful elements in the work is that
人们很容易被吸引 而不是排斥它们
people get attracted by it rather than repulsed.
艺术家
如果大家看到一件他们喜欢的东西
If I use a material which people like,
他们就会更倾向于和我交流
they are more likely to start interacting with me.
现在 这种思想可以从两个方面来解读
So now it has different aspects to it.
一个是在雕塑的建设过程中
On the one side, the sculpture installation,
人们可以从视觉的角度去享受它的美感
where it's just there to be visually perceived.
另一方面 就是和我们的行动有关了
And on the other side, a performance kind of action.
看上去很有趣吧
It looks like a lot of fun,
但是简的工作基调是十分严肃的
but Jan's work has serious undertones.
大多时候我会刻意去寻找一些
Most of the times I tried to find locations
有历史背景的地方
which have a kind of historical background
政治背景亦可
or political meaning.
现在我们是在安哈尔特火车站的后身
Today we are here in the very back of the Anhalter Bahnhof.
这里曾是柏林最大的火车站
This used to be the main train station for Berlin.
同样也是在二战结束之前
This is also a place where a lot of Jews were deported
无数犹太人被驱逐出境的地方
before the war ended.
大屠杀在我的脑海里根深蒂固
The Holocaust is an event that's omnipresent in my mind,
我常常会去想它
so I think about it a lot.
在我的作品上通常你看不到这些
You don't necessarily see it in my work,
因为我不想
because I don't want to add like,
把整个画风阴沉化
visually dark and heavy subjects.
所以我想出了用塑料积木的这样一种方法
So my idea to use the plastic construction bricks
为当代增添一抹色彩
was to add a kind of colorful part of contemporary times,
这是一种能引起全世界人共鸣的方式
a material that everybody worldwide has the same feeling on it.
一些人把这种行为艺术称为"乐高炸弹"
Some people call this type of art "LEGO bombing,"
但是简将它誉为"补丁工程"
but Jan prefers to call it "Patchwork,"
带着它走向世界
and he's bringing the patchwork project around the world.
洛桑 瑞士
基多 厄瓜多尔
特拉维夫 以色列
台北 台湾
对于我来说 看到大家都有相同的文化底蕴
For me, it's a kind of hopeful thing
其实是件让人抱有希冀的事情
to see that we actually share this common culture.
哇
Whoa...
如果你想创造出来的东西
Okay. What happens when the thing you want to build
没能问世 但取而代之地
isn't the thing that you want to build but rather
你创造出来了另外一件能代表它的东西?
a representation of the thing that you want to build?
好吧 我觉得我把自己绕进去了
Okay, I think I just confused myself.
如果你想要做出来的那个东西只是个抽象的想法呢?
What if the thing you want to build is just an idea?
乐高积木能表现出来这个想法吗?
Could LEGO bricks be used for that?
在丹麦 某个工程师
In Denmark, when a rising
要是想拿下一个大工程的建造权
architect wanted to submit for a major commission,
他会考虑一下
he looked at how modular building techniques
模块建造技术在这个国家的发展状况
had become in his home country
也会想到孩提时代最珍爱的玩具
and thought of his favorite toy as a child.
在丹麦 因为低薪资
In Denmark, because of the labor wages
建筑师
与坏天气的原因
and because of the bad weather,
你想尽可能地减少工程运作的时间
you want to minimize the time at the construction site.
所以各种细节
So everything has to be
都要提前设计好 再别具匠心地组合起来
like prefabricated elements, put together in interesting ways.
如此看来 丹麦
So in a manner of speaking, Denmark has become
似乎成为了乐高的王国
a country entirely built out of LEGO.
所以 我们想 如果是真的
So, we thought, like, if that's the truth,
我们应该向乐高致敬
why don't we make this project an homage,
所以我们将这个项目称作乐高塔
so we nicknamed the project the LEGO Towers
我们觉得 最好的方式
and thought the best way to communicate it
就是把它用乐高积木建造出来
would be to build it out of LEGO.
这个主意听上去
And the idea became almost like doing manmade mountains
像是愚公移山
that are pixilated,
像是在人造一座低分辨率的阿尔卑斯山脉
like a sort of low resolution alpine architecture.
为了向开发商说明完成这个项目有多么容易
To show the developer how easy it was to build the project,
在我们作陈述的时候
when we presented the project,
我们拿出了它的乐高模型
we also presented this LEGO model and sort of,
如果你可以用乐高搭出来它的模样
if you can build it out of LEGO,
那么这个工程还能难到哪里去啊
it can't be that difficult, can it?
然后他
And sort of he--
他把这个模型递给了他的儿子
he passed the LEGO model on to his son,
我们就这样拿到了建造权
and we got the commission.
这项工程为比亚克的团队赢得了不少赞誉
The project earned Bjarke's group a lot of critical acclaim
还为他在国际工程圈子里竖起了标杆
and helped put him on the international architecture map.
所以 在乐高公司想找人
So, when the LEGO company was looking for someone to design
在比隆建一栋乐高房子的时候
their LEGO house in Billund,
比亚克毫无疑问是最佳人选
Bjarke was the perfect choice.
当然 我们接到这个消息的时候是很激动的
Of course, we were incredibly excited to get the job.
所有丹麦人都知道 乐高是丹麦的牌子
As all Danes know, LEGO is a Danish product.
如果我的公司只为了一个目的而生
If BIG had been founded with a single purpose,
那么这个目的一定就是为了拿下乐高房子这个项目
it would be to be the architects of the LEGO house.
在剑桥的麻省理工学院 他们不仅仅在
In Cambridge, at MIT, they're using LEGO elements
剑桥 麻省
建筑上施加乐高的元素
to visualize more than just buildings.
他们在意的是整个城市的运行
They're looking at how entire cities work.
我们现在看到的是肯德尔广场的
So, we're looking at a LEGO model that has been constructed
乐高缩略模型
to represent a square kilometer of Kendall Square.
我们现在真的站在这里
We're actually in this building right here,
在麻省理工的媒体实验室里 放眼望去
in the MIT Media Lab, and overlaid on this,
你可以看到谷歌街区的投射影像
you're actually seeing a projection map of Google streets.
麻省理工的城市科学倡议协会
The MIT City Science Initiative
运用乐高的元素将风向
is using LEGO elements to visualize wind patterns,
热图像 光线 与交通流向可视化
heat maps, light studies, and traffic flow.
想看看如果这块积木得到更多的光线的话会发生什么吗
Want to see what happens if this block gets more light?
把那个十层高的楼拔起来
Just pick that 10-story building up and move it.
这个城市各个角落的复杂性
It all kind of highlights the complexity
得以呈现
of the organism that is the city.
你知道的 城市不仅仅有街道
You know, the city isn't just roads.
不是只与阳光有联系
It's not just access to sun.
在交通网络里 也不是只有人流的涌动
It's not just people moving, within the transportation networks.
万物万象 在同一地点存在着
It's all of these things, in the same place,
是极难被发现的
and that's incredibly hard to see.
它给了所有人 非专家们与半专家们
It allows everyone, let's say, non-expert and expert alike
在同一平台共事的机会
to come together on a simple platform, you know,
能加入其中 在有意义的交流中占有一席之地
that's inviting, to be for engagement,
是件很有魅力的事情
you know, in a meaningful conversation.
哇
Huh, wow.
看来乐高能帮我们解决交通问题了
Turns out LEGO bricks might solve our traffic problems.
在巴西圣保罗的贫民区
In the favelas of Sao Paulo, Brazil,
圣保罗 巴西
他们甚至将这种视化工具升华到了另一个层次
they've taken this visualization tool to the next level
他们用它来讨论想法
by using it to discuss ideas,
一些关于社会与阶层的抽象想法
abstract ideas about community and class.
我们想要求他们用乐高建设模型
We challenged them to build model cities in LEGOs,
这些建筑得以兴建
and these constructions arise out of
是因为孩子们找到了
the children's search for
总裁及创始人
解决他们社区生活麻烦的办法
solutions in the community in which they're living.
这是我们的社区 我们的生存空间
This is our community. Our space.
所有你可以想象到的东西都正在这些河流中腐烂着
Every rotten thing that you can imagine is in these rivers.
我们的朋友想搭一座桥
It was our friend who had the idea to build a bridge
借此来向社会表明它会带来什么不同
to show the difference in our society,
这也使我们得以在一个更高远的角度来看待问题
and it made us take a bigger view of things.
这显示出了改变的力量
It's showing them that the power of change,
它虽起源于一闪而过的念头
the power of an idea that begins small,
却如此具有影响力
can sometimes have a large effect.
乐高作为工具来看 还有另一种使用途径
There's another way the LEGO system is being used as a tool,
这也大概是最赋予它意义的一种途径
and perhaps the most profound of all.
玩具也可以起到治疗效果吗
Can a toy be therapeutic?
樱桃山 新泽西州
在新泽西州的樱桃山的耶鲁学校里
At the Yale School in Cherry Hill, New Jersey,
孩子们通过乐高积木在与彼此交流
kids are interacting with each other, playing with LEGO bricks.
这常见之景却一点都不平常
What seems ordinary is actually quite extraordinary.
这是一所为自闭症儿童开设的学校
This school is for kids with autism,
学校里所有的孩子都有
and all of these kids have
严重的精神系统缺陷
significant neurodevelopmental disabilities.
二十年前丹·勒高夫博士创设了一种疗法
They're part of a therapy
孩子们都是这种疗法的受众
developed two decades ago by Dr. Dan Legoff.
是的 这就是他的真名
And, yeah, that's his real name.
我是在找别的东西
I was looking for something else.
我对这些
I wasn't happy with the
用标准化方法得到的结果不太满意
outcomes I was getting using standard methods.
所以我在娱乐室里放了几张台子
And so I had, you know, different stations in my playroom.
自闭症治疗师
其中一张上面放着乐高
One of them, um, was LEGO.
很多孩子
And a lot of the kids, especially,
特别是那些对于社交感到焦虑的 害羞的
socially anxious, inhibited,
安静的 还有那些患有轻微自闭症的孩子们
quiet, mildly autistic kind of kids,
都被乐高吸引住了
gravitated to the LEGO area.
看上去那里就是一片无焦虑的小天地
And it seemed like an anxiety-free zone.
灵感始于那天
The "A-ha" Moment came
我走进等候室的时候
one day when I came out to the waiting room
看到两个孩子
and two kids that I had been seeing,
性格十分相似
very similar personalities...
他们都从家里带来乐高要给我看
they were both bringing LEGOs from home to show me.
两个人在等候室里相遇了
And they had met in the waiting room,
他们便转而向对方展示自己的积木
and they were showing each other.
他们的父母激动极了
And their parents were excited.
你能想象得到吧 他们欢呼道 "快看啊
You could tell, they were like, "Whoa. Look at that.
他们在交流 在沟通啊 太棒了"
They're communicating. They're interacting. This is cool."
勒高夫博士允许孩子们玩乐高
Dr. Legoff allowed the kids to play with LEGO toys,
前提是要求他们一起玩
but only if they built together.
三人一组 一个人是工程师
Working in groups of three, one is the engineer,
一个人负责提供材料 另外一个负责搭建
one is the parts supplier, and one is the builder.
只有交流 他们才能搭出一件完整的作品
Only by communicating can they get to a finished product.
很好
Good.
是时候转换一下角色了
This is a good time to switch.
谁还没有搭吗 这次到你了
Anybody who hasn't done building yet should take a turn now.
自闭症治疗师
整个过程进展得非常好
It's coming along real nice.
奥秘就在于让他们以集体的形式
Making them do a systematic thing
去做一件系统的事情
in a social context is the trick.
搭乐高是件很酷的事情 但是和我朋友一起搭
Building LEGOs is cool, but you know what's even better
就更酷了
is to do it with my friends.
看见这种方法奏效了 我真是太开心了
It is so exciting to see this thing working.
我的一个学生 他在乐高俱乐部里
So I have one student who interacts with other kids
与其他孩子一天的交流量
in the LEGO club much more just in that one day,
已经远远超过了他与这个俱乐部之外的孩子们的交流量
than he has interacted with kids outside of LEGO club
一整个夏天都是如此
for the whole summer.
-是吗  -这是个很重大的发现
- Right. - So that's a pretty big deal.
父母们都在这样说 "我们的孩子特别喜欢去找丹博士
Parents were saying, "Oh, my kid loves going to see Dr. Dan.
这不是很好吗 他终于有了一个他喜欢的疗法
Isn't that great? He finally has a therapy that he enjoys.
他好像比以前更善于交际了"
He seems to be getting better socially."
但是没有具体数据
But there was no data on it.
勒高夫博士进行了科学研究
Dr. Legoff conducted a scientific study
对传统疗法和他的疗法
comparing the behavioral improvements
所导致的行为上的进步进行了比较
from his therapy versus traditional therapy.
那些接受传统疗法的孩子确实有改善
Now those kids did get better.
但玩乐高的孩子比他们的改善显著的多
But the LEGO kids got significantly better than they did.
艾德里安·皮特来自纽约
One of the many kids who has benefitted
是众多受益于这种疗法的孩子之一
from this kind of therapy is Adrian Pitt, of New York City.
乐高玩具要求的就是集中精力
LEGOs are usually all about concentration.
我需要专注于更多的东西
And I need to concentrate on something a bit more.
这帮助了我 比如 更专心
It helps me, like, focus.
为什么不把帽子摘下来呢
Why don't you take off...
艾德里安他是个好孩子
Adrian is... He's just a real nice kid
他想交更多的朋友 也想玩
who wants to make friends and wants to play.
他患有语言迟缓症
He has speech and language delays,
艾德里安妈妈
3岁的时候就开始
and he has been in speech and language therapy
进行语言方面的治疗
since he was about three years old.
乐高的优越之处
The great thing about LEGO, and the reason
艾德里安爸爸
和我如此喜爱给儿子玩的原因
that I love it for him so much is there's no words.
正在于乐高不需要文字 它的指示是图片
The instructions are the pictures.
所以只要你能看见
So if you can see,
就可以遵循指示来完成乐高
you know, you can follow directions and you can complete LEGOs.
有些零件需要测量
Some of these pieces need to have measurements,
比如这块要求整好7毫米
so this one needs to be exactly seven millimeters.
这是我们测量的方法
This is how we measure.
艾德里安对他的建造感到很骄傲
Adrian's very proud of what he built.
有一种真实存在的成就感
There's a real sense of accomplishment
他完成的建造 对他而言都很重要
once he's finished something, and that's a big deal for him.
我安装这块遇到了点麻烦
I'm having a bit of trouble attaching this part.
如果我不能正确安置它 就没办法成功
If I don't get it right, then it's not going to work.
在长岛的一个秘密基地
In a secret location in Long Island,
真人大小的X-翼战机模型的组件
the components of the life-size X-Wing model
艾斯利普 纽约州
已经通过来自捷克共和国的货船运达
have arrived via freighter from the Czech Republic.
X-翼战机必须被完全组装
The X-Wing must be fully assembled,
然后分解为5个运输原件
then broken up into five transportable pieces
运送到纽约时代广场进行揭幕仪式
to be brought to New York City for its unveiling in Times Square.
时间不多了
There isn't much time.
我们终于到纽约了
We are finally in New York.
快要到最后的舞台了
We are really near to final stage.
再有几周的事了 就开始了
And it's just a couple of weeks more, and that's it.
生产部经理 乐高公司
你可以把它想象为一个巨大的儿童卧室
You can imagine this being a giant kid's bedroom,
然后我们刚刚打开了一箱砖
and we've just opened up the box of bricks,
我们已经有序的安排过每一部分了 现在开始组装了
and we've organized our parts and now we're assembling it,
和在家完成很像
a lot like you would at home.
除了这里的规模更大
Except we're just doing it on a massive scale here.
项目主管 乐高公司
这里的组装
How is this project different
与在家完成的有什么不同
from maybe the one that you build in your bedroom?
这里有重型设备负责起降
Here we have heavy equipment for lifting
5000磅和8000磅的零件
5,000-pound pieces and 8,000-pound pieces.
而且家中的模型里估计没有钢
And you probably don't have steel inside your models at home.
我们规划了日程 但就算拆开这些零件
We are on schedule, but it's-- even just unpacking the pieces,
也不是5分钟能搞定的 要花半天时间
it's not like in five minutes. It takes like half a day.
什么都需要时间 所有事加起来要几天的时间
It takes time. We need a couple of days for everything.
好的 完成了
All right, I think we got it now.
这个先来 就放那
This first, it stays where it is.
然后 引擎 最后放其他翼
Second, the engine. And then the rest of the wing.
太酷了
It's cool.
瞧 X-翼星战士
Behold, the X-Wing star fighter.
组装完成了
With the assembly complete,
现在是最大的挑战是
now comes the biggest challenge of all,
把真实大小的X-翼战机在无人发觉的前提下
bringing a life-size X-Wing
运送到美国最繁华的街区
into the busiest block in America without detection.
今天是周三 情况也许没有想象的那么糟
Today is Wednesday. It might not be that bad.
但是我们要到纽约的心脏去 所以
But we're going to the heart of New York, so...
前方还是有挑战
There are still challenges in front of us
因为我们只有最后一晚了
because we have only night until morning.
嗯 我们的计划是花整个晚上
Well, our plan is to spend the whole night
来组装它 把它们安在一起
assembling it, putting it together,
早晨6点的时候 推回来然后藏在盒子里
and at 6 A.M., roll it back and hide it inside the box.
现在是早上7点 我们搞定了
It's seven in the morning, and it's done.
艾德里安的爸爸会带他来曼哈顿中城
Adrian's father is bringing him into Midtown Manhattan
给他一份特殊惊喜
for a special surprise.
上面写什么
What does it say?
秘密模型 不可毁坏的箱子
Secret model. Indestructible box.
现场有乐高迷吗
Do we have any LEGO fans here?
有人想知道箱子里是什么吗
Does anyone here want to know what's inside that box?
-有  -听不到
- Yes! - I can't hear you!
我说 "有人想知道箱子里是什么吗"
I said, "Do you want to know what's inside that box?"
想
Yes!
大家都伸出手臂来
I want you guys to stretch your arms out all the way
利用臂力和尤达的力量
to harness the power of the
来开启这个箱子
Force along with Yoda to open up this box.
准备好了吗 一 二 三
Ready? One... two... three!
X-翼战机
X-Wing!
这个X翼星际战斗机模型
This X-Wing Starfighter is the largest LEGO model
是目前为止最大的乐高模型
that has ever been built.
用了超过500万块乐高积木
I'm talking over five million LEGO bricks.
五百三十三万五千两百块积木
Five million, three hundred, thirty-five thousand, two hundred pieces,
重四万五磅
and 45,000 pounds.
这是我见过最酷的东西
This is the coolest thing I've ever seen.
三 二 一
Three, two, one.
同样在纽约
Also in New York,
奈森·萨瓦亚在为他的个人展进行最后的准备
Nathan Sawaya is making last-minute preparations
积木梦工厂
on his one-man show, The Art of the Brick.
今晚终于开展
It finally opens tonight.
我很紧张
I am very nervous,
但也很期待看到今晚
but also very excited to see those folks
第一次穿过这道门的人们
walk through the door for the first time tonight.
这里是积木梦工厂
This is The Art of the Brick.
这是我举办过的最大型展览
This is my largest exhibition I've ever done,
也恰巧是
and it just happens to be
个人举办的最大乐高展
the largest solo LEGO art exhibition ever.
把乐高带入当代艺术世界是我的目标
I had a goal of taking LEGO into the contemporary art world,
为了实现它
and to do so, it had to be done in a way
我必须全身心地投入进去
where I was really putting myself and my soul into the work.
我都想变成墙上的苍蝇
You know, part of me wants to just be a fly on the wall
来听听大家的反应
and listen to people's reaction.
我会尽量这么做的
And I'm going to try and do that as much as possible.
嗯 我们拭目以待吧
So, um, we'll see what happens.
好的 谢谢你
There it is, thank you.
第一反应直接被惊呆了
First impression, I just got blown away.
没想过能感受到如此巨大的灵感
I didn't expect to feel this much inspiration.
太赞了 我小时候玩过乐高
Amazing. I worked with LEGO when I was a kid,
但都按着图纸做
but I always built things off the back of the packet,
我从未想过有人把它变成自己脑海中的东西
and I can't believe that someone's actually turned around
然后做出来展出
and turned it into something from their imagination.
这是很愉悦有趣的事物
This is something that is delightful and playful,
也是一些可以
and it's something that can really
激发孩子和成人的灵感的东西
spark the imagination in children and adults.
已经有几个艺术评论家走过去了
We have had a few art critics walk through already,
当然我也很紧张他们会怎么说
and of course I'm nervous to see what they say,
但我认为只要有主流媒体的
but I think it's almost a compliment
专业艺术评论家过来
just to have a serious art critic from some
就已经是一种赞美了
major newspapers in this country walking through.
他们不会错认为这只是个玩具展
They were not dismissing it as just a toy display.
这不只是个噱头 这是艺术
It's not just a gimmick. This was art.
你们怎么看
What do you guys think?
-我们觉得很棒  -是吧
- I think it's good. - Yeah?
-是你做的吗  -是 这些都是我做的
- Did you make that? - I did, I made all of these.
这种形式的展览将会把那些
This type of exhibition is going to draw in folks
从未参观过美术博物馆的人吸引过来
who have never been to an art museum before in their life.
他们过来是因为对玩具有种熟悉感
And they're coming because they have a familiarity with the toy.
如果这为他们
And if that opens them up
第一次开启了艺术世界的大门 我就成功了
to the art world for the first time, then I've done my job.
乐高设计者詹米·贝拉尔德正前往西雅图的乐高积木展
LEGO Designer Jamie Berard is headed to BrickCon in Seattle
乐高设计师
为他的新设计巴黎式小餐馆揭幕
to unveil his new Parisian Cafe set.
但他在那还有另一个任务
But while he's there, he's got another mission.
这是我们的开心盒 现在我们不知道这里边有什么
These are our happy boxes. Now, we don't know what's in this.
他在说服他的设计师们
He's convinced his fellow designers
与粉丝进行模型构建大赛
to compete against the public in the master build contest.
好的大伙们
Okay, teams.
这和我们将在华盛顿西雅图的乐高积木展
These are the same products that will be given to LEGO fans
给乐高迷的产品是一样的
at BrickCon in Seattle, Washington.
我们想让大家真正参与到活动中
And what we want to do is actually participate more in the event
和乐高迷一起接受挑战
by doing the challenge they
我们先在这实战演示下
will be doing there, we'll be doing it here.
西雅图 华盛顿州
欢迎
Welcome!
好的 你们发现只有25个位置
Okay, you notice there are only 25 stations.
挑个组员一起坐下吧
Pick a teammate and go sit down.
我觉得乐高积木展大会一定会很有趣
I think it's going to be a lot of fun at the BrickCon convention,
因为当你有机会与设计者当面交锋
because when you have a head-to-head with designers,
乐高设计师
你肯定想战胜他们
of course you want to beat them.
好的 我们都有什么
All right, so what do we got here?
-好的 很棒  -我们的角度是什么
- Okay, that's cool. - What is our angle going to be?
你们可以看到猪和牛的头是因为
The reason that you can see we have pig and cow heads,
今年乐高积木展的主题
is because the theme for
是猪牛对战
this year's BrickCon is Pigs Versus Cows.
每个人都有两个牛头和猪头吗
Does everyone have two pig heads and two cow heads?
还有问题吗
Are there any questions?
-有  -就一个"自己的创作"吗
- Yes. - It's one MOC?
乐高中的MOC代表着My Own Creation,"我自己的创造"
是一个 但想有多少楼都可以
It's one MOC, but it can be how many buildings you want.
尽可能的构建故事吧
Make up the story as much as you want,
然后从中获得乐趣
and then have a lot of fun with it.
用所有的零件 所有布景 想要多少都行
Use all the pieces, use all the set, as much as you like.
你们有一个半小时 准备好了吗
You'll have one and one half hours to build. Are we ready?
好了
Yeah!
开始
Go!
背后的故事是
So, the idea behind this
他们应该为某些东西而战
is that they should be fighting for something.
这是一场战争 或是某种猪牛大战
It's a battle or some type of pigs versus cows.
看吧 总是这样
See, this is always like, you know,
为什么一定要有争斗呢
why does it always have to be battles?
没准哪个赢了才能生存
Maybe whoever wins stays alive.
-生存  -是的
- Stays alive. - Yeah.
选手们 你们现在
Contestants, you now have
只有59分51秒了
fifty-nine minutes and fifty-one seconds left!
压力
Pressure!
噢 压力 我讨厌在压力下建造东西
Oh, stress! I hate building under stress.
怎么样了 有什么进展
How are things going, what's your process here?
你可以拿任何东西创建任何东西
You can build anything with anything.
对 对
Right, right.
所以 先想个好故事
So, come up with a good story first,
然后用零件造出你们想要的故事
and then make the pieces do what you need them to do.
-有意思  -创作一个故事
- Interesting. - Build a story.
这是我们第一次听到有人这样谈论故事
This is the first time we've heard someone talking about story,
这对这场比赛很重要
which I know was very important in this contest.
他像个机械牛 所以他是半牛半械
He's like a cyborg. So he's half-cow, half-robot.
-是滴  -是的
- Yeah. - Yes.
-这是个机械牛  -噢 是个好主意
- It's a "Cowborg." - Oh, that's a good idea.
-我需要更大的角吗  -要啊 多点角
- Do I need bigger horns? - Yeah, much more horny.
你这个猪
You pig.
有些故事
Some of the stories at some
在某个点变得很荒诞和疯狂
point just got really ridiculous and crazy.
但是 因为我们是去粉丝活动嘛
And yet, because we were going to a fan event,
比平常的设计更进一步
it was kinda fun to let it almost progress
也是挺有趣的
a little bit further than we normally would.
这是个牛牛弹射车
It's a "Cow-tapult."
戴夫 史黛西比赛进行的怎么样了
Dave, Stacy, how's the competition going so far?
我们还剩很多块 但我觉得我们找对方向的
We have a lot of pieces, but I think we're on the right track.
乔西跟我们讲讲你们的设计呗
Josh, why don't you tell us what you guys are working on?
我们设计了这个臭名昭彰的小房子
We have a little house of ill repute going on here.
这是个牛牛俱乐部 但猪们进来了
It's a cow club, but the pigs have come in.
他正在灌木丛边上尿尿
He's relieving himself in the bush right here.
对 他速度超快
Yeah, he's super-fast.
他在这家伙边上转啊转
He's turning round, round this guy.
我期待有人看到这些然后说
I'm expecting some people to look at them and go...
来真的吗 这就是你最高水平了
Really? Is this the best you got?
乐高迷们不知道
The LEGO fans don't know
他们会与乐高的设计者进行竞争
they'll be competing against LEGO designers
直到詹米的出现
until Jamie shows up.
我必须看看你的动物
I just have to look at your animal
因为我们试图看清你们是怎么做的
because we were trying to see how you did it.
他让我们有点难堪
He's making us look bad.
时间到
Time's up!
我们做完了
We finished.
确保你们的创作设计是你们想要的效果
Make sure your MOC is arranged the way you want it to be seen.
出门稍候 十分钟以后进来
Step outside and come back in ten minutes.
恭喜
Congratulations!
叫他们进来吧 让他们知道发生了什么
Let's bring them in, let them know what's going on.
你们做得都太棒了
You guys did such a great job,
很难分出谁是冠军
it was really hard to tell who was our champion.
所以 八号 请你站在你的模型旁边好吗
so, Number 8, won't you stand by your MOC, please?
赢者是八号
Winner is Number 8!
我们基本是分开的 一人建了一个机械
We basically split off. We each built a mech.
我建的是猪械 Chris建的是牛械
So I built the pig mech, and Chris built the cow mech.
所以他们有点像机器人拳击赛
So they're kind of like Rock 'Em Sock 'Em Robots?
嗯 我们真正喜欢这个创作
Yeah, I think what we really liked about the MOC,
也是你们赢的原因是
and what made it really win, was the fact that
你们不仅利用了提供的牛头和猪头
not only did you use the small pig and cow heads here,
而且用提供的乐高积木
but you also constructed robotic ones from scratch
快速构建了一个机械物
with the bricks you were provided.
胜者真的 我绝对同意 很杰出
The winner was, I definitely agree-- was really a standout.
我知道我们的竞争会很激烈
I knew we'd have tough competition.
这些都是很棒的建造家
These are some really amazing builders.
我的意思是 我真的认为
I mean, I'd like to think that
我们进了前28就很好了
we came in the top 28, which was pretty good.
模型建结束不多久后
Shortly after the master build,
詹米隆重介绍了巴黎式小餐馆套装
Jamie introduces the new Parisian Cafe set to much fanfare.
然后参与者都集聚到
Then participants gather in
中央大厅来进行年度颁奖庆典
the main hall for the annual award ceremony.
爱丽丝·芬奇的瑞文戴尔被选出为
Alice Finch's Rivendell build is being considered
梦寐以求的人民选择奖
for the coveted People's Choice Award.
人民选择奖是由公众投票的
The People's Choice Awards are those voted upon by the public.
我们计算所有选票 然后得出
We counted all those up, and we came up with
人民选择奖的得主
Winners of People's Choice.
获奖作品是
And the winner is...
瑞文戴尔
Rivendell!
有一万人为喜欢你的作品
It's a pretty amazing feeling to have
这是一种很赞的感觉
10,000 people say that they like what you build.
女人获奖不很普遍
To have a woman win is pretty unusual.
连续三年都是同一个人的还没有听过
To have the same person win three years in a row is unheard of.
了解人类和我们的历史
One of the fundamental ways we know about humans
一种很基础的方式就是看他们建造的东西
and our history is by the things that they build.
也许一些小的塑料砖块是新时代的一种适应
Maybe little plastic bricks are a modern adaptation of that,
但本质是建造东西
but really it's about creating something.
我们触碰到的绝对是人类的核心
We are definitely at the core of what is human,
就是建造东西的能力
is the capacity to build.
从大局来看 地球上的生物已经进化了几千年
In the big picture, life on Earth has evolved through millennia
来适应周遭环境
by adapting to the surroundings,
直到某一点 我们制造了工具 科技
until the point where we invent tools, technology.
我们突然得到了适应我们生活环境的能力
We suddenly get the capacity to adapt our surroundings to life.
所以我们不必再寻找可以容身的穴洞
So we now no longer have to suffice
或是可以爬上的树木
with a cave we can find or a tree we can climb into.
我们可以建造自己的洞穴
We can actually build our own cave,
可以建自己的树屋
and we can build our own tree house.
当我们拥有这种能力的瞬间
The moment where we really became human
就是我们成为真正人类的时候
was the moment where we got this power.
这也是一种心态
It's also a mindset somehow.
就是相信只要手边有工具
It's believing that anything is possible
那么凡事皆有可能
if you have the right tools in front of you.
有时候我们没有机会去自由的抒发
Sometimes we don't have an opportunity to just be free,
我们内心的世界
and everything that we have inside of us,
从没有机会真正得以释放
we never have an opportunity to let it out.
我们一直在寻找启发我们
And we're always looking for something to inspire us
或是给予我们快乐的东西
or to just give us some joy.
能让我们心中的梦和思想
Being able to take your dreams and take your thoughts
变得实体化
and materialize into something,
这是个美妙的礼物
it's just a wonderful gift,
我认为乐高积木给予世界这样的礼物
and I think the LEGO brick has given that to the world.
在爱达荷州 乔纳森和马特马上完成
In Idaho, Jonathan and Matt are nearly finished editing
他们的杰作《熔点》
their masterpiece, Melting Point.
X翼战机已经永久的降落在了德国法兰克福
The X-Wing has landed permanently in Frankfurt, Germany.
在哥本哈根 索伦仍在试图弄清
In Copenhagen, Soren is still trying to figure out
无限的可能性
just how infinite the possibilities are.
在捷克共和国斯蒂芬的好奇号火星车
And in the Czech Republic, Stephen's Curiosity Rover
终于正式进入了流水线
is finally rolling off the assembly line.
哇哦 好多漫步者 赞
Oh wow, that's a lot of rovers. Awesome.
包装设计真的很漂亮
That's really nice-looking box art.
嗯 是啊 这就是Cuusoo的优点
Oh, yeah, that's the great thing about Cuusoo sets,
他们有最好的包装盒子
they have the best boxes.
-哇哦 我在这  -找到你了
- Oh, there I am. It's me. - There you are.
"我希望这个模型
"It's my hope that this model
能鼓励大家
encourages the public support
公众的支持是持续发展和
that is integral to the continued development
探索更广阔宇宙空间必不可缺的" 对
and exploration of outer space." Yeah.
我很开心 史蒂芬提到了空间
I'm glad Stephen mentioned space.
我们的影片不就是从这里开始的吗
Didn't we start this film out there?
我保证我们会解释的
I promised we'd explain that,
现在快到这影片的结尾了
and seeing how this is the end of the movie,
现在是时候了 为了那个故事
now is the time. For that story,
我们去了加州的帕萨迪纳市
we go to Pasadena, California,
美国国家航空航天局的喷气推进实验室 或者简称JPL
and NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratories, or JPL for short.
作为工程师和科学家
As engineers and scientists
他们通过开发宇宙飞船的想法和任务
are developing space craft ideas and missions
去探索宇宙 了解太空
to go out and explore and learn about the universe,
美国航空航天局科学家
我们有时候会用乐高来建立一种概念
we sometimes use LEGOs to kinda put together a concept
然后看看是否合理
and see if it makes sense.
所以JPL有间房子叫怪诞想法
So there's a room here at JPL called the Left Field,
真的有这些玩具 有点像孩子的梦想
and it actually has these toys, sort of a kid's dream.
有大盒的乐高 科学家和工程师
Has big boxes of LEGOs, and scientists and engineers
聚在一起真正的构架一些东西
get together and actually construct something
看起来有点像他们想要的宇宙飞船
that looks a little bit like the spacecraft they want.
搭载前往木星的朱诺一号运载火箭 阿特拉斯五号发射升空
Lift off of the Atlas 5 with Juno on a trek to Jupiter
朱诺计划是2011年8月启动的
The Juno project is a NASA mission
美国航天局使命 前往木星
that was launched in August of 2011 to go to Jupiter,
我们会用仪器
and we will use our
来研究木星的构造
instruments to learn about Jupiter's formation
和其他太阳系行星的信息
and other solar systems around other stars.
但是乐高不仅仅是设计程序的一部分
But the LEGO system was not just a part of the design process.
我们坐上飞船了
We're onboard!
美国航天局的工程师把我三个铝制朋友
NASA engineers have mounted three aluminum friends of mine
挂载在朱诺号船体上
to the hull of the Juno spacecraft.
这三个小人分别以科学家伽利略
The three minifigures are modeled after Galileo the scientist,
朱庇特大神和朱诺女神为模板
Jupiter the god, and the goddess Juno.
他们被安在宇宙飞船的主甲板上
They're attached to the main deck of the spacecraft.
他们是乐高公司用符合美航局规范的
They were made by the LEGO company, to NASA specifications,
特殊航天器级别铝制造的
of a special spacecraft-grade aluminum.
有时候我会想
Sometimes I imagine,
他们会在航行中看到什么
what are they seeing in their voyage?
他们可以看到美不胜收的景色
They're able to see this incredible view.
事实上 他们会看到我们都梦寐以求的风光
In fact, they're seeing the view that we all want to see.
这些乐高小人代表了我们
We're living vicariously through these LEGO minifigures.
他们在很多方面代表了人类
They represent humanity in many ways.
宇宙中几乎所有事物都由别的东西构建而成
Almost everything in the universe is built from something else,
有些基本的组成单位 像是原子或分子
some fundamental building block like an atom or a molecule,
于我而言 乐高就代表了
and for me, LEGO represents
这样的一种基本单位
one of those fundamental building blocks.
看看我们利用这个简单的玩具做了多少东西
And look how many things we've built from this simple toy.
-开拍  -开拍
- Action. - Action.
切
Cut!
放出猎犬
Release the hounds!
额 那是个笑话吗
Now, was that-- was this a joke?
难道这应该搞笑吗 因为我不知道
Was this supposed to be funny? 'Cause I don't know if I...
我真的搞不懂 谁写的这个
I certainly don't get this. Who wrote this?